<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pigalle Discotheque and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</title>
    <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/pigalle-discotheque-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pigalle Discotheque and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/pigalle-discotheque-and-casino-las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering Pigalle Discotheque and Casino - A 1970s Flash on the Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pigalle-discotheque-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pigalle-discotheque-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-parisian-spark-on-the-las-vegas-strip-pigalle-discotheque--casino&#34;&gt;A Parisian Spark on the Las Vegas Strip: Pigalle Discotheque &amp;amp; Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been about reinvention. But some eras represent particularly dramatic shifts. The mid-1970s were one such time, and nestled amongst the familiar neon and casino sparkle was a club that stood apart: Pigalle Discotheque and Casino. Its story, though short, provides a fascinating glimpse into a fleeting moment in Las Vegas history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rise-of-pigalle-a-daring-concept&#34;&gt;The Rise of Pigalle: A Daring Concept&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around 1974, Pigalle boldly took over a prime corner location on the Strip, specifically at Sands Avenue (now Las Vegas Boulevard South). Situated right beside the Rose Bowl Race Book, and soon followed by the famously flamboyant Dirty Sally’s, Pigalle’s arrival was visually striking. The name itself was a statement, a deliberate nod to the Parisian Pigalle district, renowned for its cabarets and a certain &lt;em&gt;je ne sais quoi&lt;/em&gt; – a touch of bohemian flair and, let’s be honest, a reputation for risqué entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
