<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Royal Inn Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/royal-inn-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link><description>Recent content in Royal Inn Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/royal-inn-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Royal Inn Hotel and Casino: A Forgotten Gem on the East Strip | Vintage Las Vegas History</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-inn-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-inn-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-humble-beginning-the-royal-inn-joins-the-strip"&gt;A Humble Beginning: The &lt;a href="https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-casino-las-vegas/"&gt;Royal&lt;/a&gt; Inn Joins the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wasn’t always the glitzy behemoth it is today. Back in the late 1960s, it was still evolving, finding its identity. Enter the Royal Inn Hotel and Casino, a property that, while modest compared to the giants already present, represents a fascinating snapshot of that era. Construction began in August 1969, a flurry of activity marking its debut. On April 19, 1970, the Royal Inn opened its doors, a 12-story, 200-room hotel nestled on six acres just east of the main Strip. It was part of the Royal Inns of America chain, a national brand aiming to capture a piece of the burgeoning hospitality market. At $3 million, it was a relatively modest investment, reflecting its intention to cater to a different kind of traveler – one seeking affordability and convenience rather than lavish extravagance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>