<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Binions Horseshoe Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</title>
    <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/binions-horseshoe-las-vegas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Binions Horseshoe Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/binions-horseshoe-las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Binion’s Horseshoe Las Vegas: A Downtown Legend and the Birth of the WSOP | Vintage Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/binions-horseshoe-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/binions-horseshoe-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;binions-horseshoe-las-vegas-where-legends-were-made&#34;&gt;Binion’s Horseshoe Las Vegas: Where Legends Were Made&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas wasn’t always the glitzy playground we know today. In the early 1950s, it was a rough-and-tumble frontier town, and Benny Binion was determined to change it. In 1951, he opened the Horseshoe at 128 Fremont Street, instantly establishing himself as a pivotal figure in Las Vegas history. This wasn’t just another casino; it was a statement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-gamblers-paradise-defined&#34;&gt;A Gambler’s Paradise Defined&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Binion, a shrewd and charismatic Texan, brought a new philosophy to Vegas. He believed in fair odds, generous limits – often no-limit – and treating every gambler with respect. Forget the stuffy, formal atmosphere of the nascent Las Vegas Strip; the Horseshoe offered a welcoming vibe where a nickel bet was treated with the same courtesy as a thousand-dollar one. This “treat everyone like a king” approach was a game-changer, attracting a clientele seeking a more authentic and approachable gambling experience. That personalized service and friendly atmosphere became the Horseshoe&amp;rsquo;s hallmarks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
