<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Landmark Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</title>
    <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/landmark-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Landmark Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/landmark-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lost Oasis: The Rise and Fall of the Landmark Hotel and Casino - Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/landmark-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/landmark-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-dream-deferred-the-story-of-the-landmark-hotel-and-casino&#34;&gt;A Dream Deferred: The Story of the Landmark Hotel and Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of us who cherish vintage Las Vegas, the memory of the Landmark Hotel and Casino represents a bittersweet chapter. Located just off the Strip, in what is now Winchester, Nevada, the Landmark’s story is one of big ambitions, frustrating delays, and ultimately, a failure to thrive in an increasingly competitive landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-caroll-era--early-challenges-1961-1968&#34;&gt;The Caroll Era &amp;amp; Early Challenges (1961-1968)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Frank Caroll, a familiar name in early Vegas gaming, envisioned a grand resort in 1961. He purchased the land and quickly began construction, initially focusing on a shopping center and apartments which opened by the end of 1961. A towering hotel-casino was next, construction beginning in September of the same year. Initial progress was promising, with around 80% of the tower taking shape by 1962. However, funding proved to be a major hurdle, bringing construction to a standstill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
