<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Club Bingo Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</title>
    <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/club-bingo-las-vegas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Club Bingo Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/club-bingo-las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Club Bingo: A Vintage Vegas History Lesson</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/club-bingo-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/club-bingo-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-strip-standalone-to-fremont-street-flair-the-story-of-club-bingo-las-vegas&#34;&gt;From Strip Standalone to Fremont Street Flair: The Story of Club Bingo Las Vegas&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before mega-resorts and dazzling spectacles, Las Vegas thrived on simpler pleasures. Among them? Bingo! And for a time, Club Bingo was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to be for locals and tourists alike. Its story offers a fascinating glimpse into the evolution of Las Vegas entertainment, showcasing two distinct eras.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-original-a-post-war-strip-landmark&#34;&gt;The Original: A Post-War Strip Landmark&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Club Bingo first burst onto the scene on July 24, 1947, at 2535 South Las Vegas Boulevard. Imagine the Strip back then - less glitzy, more modest. Milton Prell and Al Winter, seasoned gaming entrepreneurs, envisioned a dedicated 300-seat bingo parlor, complete with the appealing addition of a “Bonanza Room” for dining and entertainment. Managed by Frank Schivo, Club Bingo quickly became a beloved local hangout. It wasn’t a grand palace – the design was intentionally understated – but its electric bingo board sign, a beacon of neon fun, made it instantly recognizable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
