<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Park Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/the-park-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link><description>Recent content in The Park Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/the-park-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Remembering The Park Hotel and Casino: A Downtown Las Vegas History Lesson</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-park-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-park-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="from-holiday-cheer-to-the-park-a-downtown-beginning"&gt;From &lt;a href="https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holiday-casino-las-vegas/"&gt;Holiday&lt;/a&gt; Cheer to The Park: A Downtown Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas has seen its share of comings and goings. Many hotels and casinos have graced the Fremont Street experience, only to vanish into &lt;a href="https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-sands-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/"&gt;the sands&lt;/a&gt; of time. Today, we’re revisiting one of those – The Park Hotel and Casino, a property whose life was surprisingly brief, yet packed with significant events in Las Vegas history. Originally opening in 1978 as the &lt;a href="https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holiday-international-casino-las-vegas/"&gt;Holiday International&lt;/a&gt;, the hotel was built near Fremont Street, a key location as downtown remained the heart of Vegas entertainment. The Holiday &lt;a href="https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/international-hotel-las-vegas/"&gt;International&lt;/a&gt; was a significant addition to the area, boasting 406 rooms and aiming to capture the tourist trade that still flocked to the city&amp;rsquo;s original gaming district. It presented a modern, somewhat international aesthetic, fitting with the name and reflecting a broader appeal than some of the more traditionally themed casinos nearby.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>