<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fortune Club Hotel and Casino Las Legas on Vintage Vegas</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/fortune-club-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link><description>Recent content in Fortune Club Hotel and Casino Las Legas on Vintage Vegas</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/fortune-club-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lost in the Glitter: The Original Fortune Club Hotel &amp; Casino - Vintage Vegas History</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fortune-club-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fortune-club-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-fleeting-fortune-on-fremont-street"&gt;A Fleeting Fortune on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1950s were a vital period in Las Vegas&amp;rsquo;s development. Downtown, clustered around Fremont Street, was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to be. Amidst the emerging casinos and burgeoning neon, the Fortune Club Hotel &amp;amp; Casino briefly shone from 1953 to 1958 at 109 Fremont Street. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t destined for long-term glory, but its story highlights the cutthroat, often messy, reality of early Vegas business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-dream-team--early-days"&gt;The Dream Team &amp;amp; Early Days&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original Fortune Club was the brainchild of a trio: Cecil Lynch, Harry Gordon, and Robert Van Santen. Together, they launched a classic Downtown offering - a modest hotel and casino featuring slots, blackjack, and bingo. These games were the bedrock of early Las Vegas entertainment, attracting a steady stream of visitors eager to try their luck. While information about the club&amp;rsquo;s early operation is sparse, it undoubtedly contributed to the bustling atmosphere of Fremont Street during that era. Photos of the time show a simple, clean design, reflecting the relatively understated aesthetic of the early Vegas experience, quite different from the themed mega-resorts that would later dominate the Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>