<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Key Largo Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/key-largo-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link><description>Recent content in Key Largo Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/key-largo-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Key Largo Hotel and Casino Las Vegas: A Forgotten Oasis on Flamingo Road | Vintage Vegas History</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/key-largo-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/key-largo-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-shifting-identity-from-ambassador-to-key-largo"&gt;A Shifting Identity: From Ambassador to Key Largo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The corner of East Flamingo Road and &lt;a href="https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/paradise-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/"&gt;Paradise&lt;/a&gt; Road has seen a lot of change over the decades, but for many vintage Las Vegas enthusiasts, the memory of the Key Largo Hotel and Casino holds a certain nostalgic charm. Its journey wasn&amp;rsquo;t straightforward, marked by multiple name changes and a slow fade into oblivion. Originally opening in 1974 as the Ambassador Inn, it was a modest motel catering to travelers looking for affordable lodging a little removed from the glitz and glamour of the burgeoning Las Vegas Strip. The addition of a casino in 1978 signaled an attempt to capitalize on Nevada’s booming gambling industry. It was known then simply as the &lt;a href="https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/ambassador-casino-las-vegas/"&gt;Ambassador Casino&lt;/a&gt;. Subsequent iterations included the Paradise Inn and the Quality Inn Key Largo Casino, each reflecting a period of shifting ownership and rebranding attempts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>