<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vintage Vegas</title>
    <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/vintage-vegas/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vintage Vegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/vintage-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;I Lost My A in Las Vegas&#39;: A Mysterious Matchbook &amp; the Glittering 1970s Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/i-lost-my-a-in-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/i-lost-my-a-in-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-matchbook-mystery-i-lost-my-a-in-las-vegas&#34;&gt;A Matchbook Mystery: &amp;ldquo;I Lost My A in Las Vegas&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve all seen the iconic matchbooks advertising Las Vegas hotels, a tangible souvenir from a bygone era. But some are more enigmatic than others. This little gem, &amp;ldquo;I Lost My A in Las Vegas,&amp;rdquo; is one such mystery. It&amp;rsquo;s not just a piece of ephemera; it&amp;rsquo;s a tiny portal to a specific time and place on the Las Vegas Strip - likely the mid-1970s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I Lost My A in Las Vegas”: A Mysterious Matchbook &amp; The Glory Days of the Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/i-lost-my-a-in-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/i-lost-my-a-in-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-lost-my-a-in-las-vegas-a-matchbook-mystery&#34;&gt;“I Lost My A in Las Vegas”: A Matchbook Mystery&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vintage Las Vegas is full of ephemera – cocktail napkins, playing cards, show programs – that offer fleeting glimpses into a bygone era. Among the most intriguing of these relics is a promotional matchbook bearing the cryptic phrase, “I Lost My A in Las Vegas.” Its mystery deepens the further you dig, offering a unique window into the 1970s, a decade of immense change and extravagant growth for the Las Vegas Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Downtown Icon: The Enduring History of the El Cortez Hotel and Casino Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-cortez-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-cortez-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-than-just-a-casino-the-el-cortezs-story-begins&#34;&gt;More Than Just a Casino: The El Cortez&amp;rsquo;s Story Begins&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The El Cortez Hotel and Casino, affectionately known as “El Co” by locals, is a cornerstone of Downtown Las Vegas. Opened on November 7, 1941, it stands as a proud testament to the city’s enduring spirit and its evolution from a dusty desert town to a global entertainment hub. To understand the El Cortez is to understand a significant piece of vintage Las Vegas history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Look Back: The Iconic Vintage Vegas Logos That Defined an Era</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/vintage-vegas-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/vintage-vegas-logo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-look-back-the-iconic-vintage-vegas-logos-that-defined-an-era&#34;&gt;A Look Back: The Iconic Vintage Vegas Logos That Defined an Era&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip. Just the name conjures images of shimmering neon, extravagant shows, and a palpable sense of possibility. But before the mega-resorts and modern marvels, there was a distinct aesthetic – one powerfully communicated through logo design. At Vintage Vegas Shirts, we celebrate that legacy, and we thought we&amp;rsquo;d take a trip down memory lane to examine some of the most iconic vintage Vegas logos and the stories they tell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Star&#39;s Gamble: The Rise and Fall of the Debbie Reynolds Hotel &amp; Casino - Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/debbie-reynolds-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/debbie-reynolds-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-hollywood-icon-tries-her-hand-at-vegas&#34;&gt;A Hollywood Icon Tries Her Hand at Vegas&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 1990s Las Vegas Strip was a landscape of ambitious expansion and ever-more-extravagant themes. Amidst this frenzy, in 1992, actress Debbie Reynolds, a true Hollywood legend, made a bold move: she and her then-husband, Richard Hamlett, purchased the Paddlewheel Hotel and Casino for $2.2 million. The plan? To transform it into a dazzling tribute to Hollywood’s golden age, complete with a museum showcasing Reynolds’ incredible collection of movie memorabilia. It was a dream project, a chance to blend her two worlds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Timeless Landmark: The History of the Gateway Motel Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/gateway-motel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/gateway-motel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-auto-court-to-iconic-motel-the-early-days&#34;&gt;From Auto Court to Iconic Motel: The Early Days&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling shows, Las Vegas Boulevard was a dusty stretch of Highway 91 connecting the city to Los Angeles. And for travelers needing a place to rest their weary heads, the Gateway Auto Court appeared in 1931. Founded by Gabriel Paher and his son Stanley M. Paher, it initially consisted of 27 simple, Spanish-tiled cabins, each boasting a convenient carport for those cross-country road trips. The price? Just $1 a night – a remarkably affordable rate considering the limited options available at the time. This wasn’t about luxury; it was about providing a reliable, no-frills stopping point for those traversing the desert landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ahoy, History Buffs! Uncovering the Lost Pirate Charm of Buccaneer Bar Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/buccaneer-bar-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/buccaneer-bar-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-pirates-life-for-a-las-vegas-bar-briefly&#34;&gt;A Pirate&amp;rsquo;s Life for a Las Vegas Bar (Briefly!)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas, particularly the legendary El Cortez Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, has a rich and vibrant history. Among its many transformations, one particularly quirky chapter involved the Buccaneer Bar. While it’s a relatively short but fascinating story, it exemplifies a time when Vegas embraced themed entertainment to draw in crowds and create immersive experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Originally opening in 1941, the El Cortez underwent significant renovations in the mid-1940s under the direction of founder J. Kell Houssels. These improvements, including a new nightclub and pool, paved the way for something truly unique: a pirate-themed bar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Benny Binion&#39;s Horseshoe: A Vintage Las Vegas Legend and the Birth of the WSOP</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/benny-binions-horseshoe-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/benny-binions-horseshoe-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-binion-revolution-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;The Binion Revolution on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts of the Las Vegas Strip dominated the skyline, downtown Fremont Street was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to be. And at the heart of its vibrant, sometimes rough-and-tumble, casino scene stood the Horseshoe, founded in 1951 by the legendary Benny Binion. Binion wasn’t just opening a casino; he was creating a gambler’s paradise, a direct challenge to the more formal and restrictive environments prevalent at the time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binion’s Horseshoe Las Vegas: A Downtown Legend and the Birth of the WSOP | Vintage Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/binions-horseshoe-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/binions-horseshoe-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;binions-horseshoe-las-vegas-where-legends-were-made&#34;&gt;Binion’s Horseshoe Las Vegas: Where Legends Were Made&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas wasn’t always the glitzy playground we know today. In the early 1950s, it was a rough-and-tumble frontier town, and Benny Binion was determined to change it. In 1951, he opened the Horseshoe at 128 Fremont Street, instantly establishing himself as a pivotal figure in Las Vegas history. This wasn’t just another casino; it was a statement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-gamblers-paradise-defined&#34;&gt;A Gambler’s Paradise Defined&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Binion, a shrewd and charismatic Texan, brought a new philosophy to Vegas. He believed in fair odds, generous limits – often no-limit – and treating every gambler with respect. Forget the stuffy, formal atmosphere of the nascent Las Vegas Strip; the Horseshoe offered a welcoming vibe where a nickel bet was treated with the same courtesy as a thousand-dollar one. This “treat everyone like a king” approach was a game-changer, attracting a clientele seeking a more authentic and approachable gambling experience. That personalized service and friendly atmosphere became the Horseshoe&amp;rsquo;s hallmarks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blast Off to the Past: Remembering Vegas World Hotel and Casino – A Vintage Las Vegas Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/vegas-world-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/vegas-world-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-phoenix-rises-from-ashes-to-intergalactic-resort&#34;&gt;A Phoenix Rises: From Ashes to Intergalactic Resort&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the Stratosphere pierced the Las Vegas skyline, there was Vegas World Hotel &amp;amp; Casino. Opened on July 13, 1979, by the irrepressible Bob Stupak, Vegas World wasn’t just a casino; it was an experience. Stupak famously transformed a burned-out slot parlor into a sprawling, space-themed wonderland, embracing the mantra, “The Sky’s the Limit.” This was a period of Vegas pushing boundaries, and Stupak was at the forefront of the charge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buckley’s Jackpot Club: A Glimpse into Vintage Las Vegas Slot Machine Mania</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/buckleys-jackpot-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/buckleys-jackpot-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-small-club-a-big-promise-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Small Club, a Big Promise on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and sprawling Strip, Las Vegas was built on a different kind of charm. Downtown, on what is now Fremont Street Experience, lay “Glitter Gulch,” a vibrant corridor lined with smaller, independently operated casinos. Among these was Buckley’s Jackpot Club, a brief but memorable fixture at 20 Fremont Street from 1952 to approximately 1960. It’s a reminder of a pivotal era in Las Vegas history, one where the simple thrill of a slot machine reigned supreme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Centerfold Casino Las Vegas: A Brief, Bold Flash on the Strip&#39;s History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/centerfold-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/centerfold-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-risqué-reign-on-the-boulevard-1975-1977&#34;&gt;A Risqué Reign on the Boulevard (1975-1977)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Along the south Strip, near Sahara Avenue, a particular stretch has seen more transformations than most. Among them stands a location at 2440 Las Vegas Boulevard South that in 1975 became the Centerfold Casino. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fresh plot of land; it had previously cycled through names like Honest John’s Casino and housed the iconic Big Wheel, a testament to the ever-evolving nature of Vegas entertainment. Centerfold, however, took a distinct turn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding the Glamour: A History of Vintage Las Vegas Logos</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/vintag-vegas-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/vintag-vegas-logo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-visual-language-of-dreams-vintage-vegas-logos&#34;&gt;A Visual Language of Dreams: Vintage Vegas Logos&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas, the Entertainment Capital of the World, isn’t just about shows and gaming; it’s a carefully constructed fantasy, and a huge part of that fantasy was, and remains, its branding. Those iconic vintage Las Vegas logos – the swirling fonts, the stylized imagery, the unapologetic boldness – weren&amp;rsquo;t just identifiers; they were promises of luxury, excitement, and escape. Here at Vintage Vegas Shirts, we’re passionate about preserving that visual legacy, and understanding its history is key to appreciating its magic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diamond Jim&#39;s Nevada Club Casino: A Flashy Slice of Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/diamond-jims-nevada-club-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/diamond-jims-nevada-club-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-short-bright-life-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Short, Bright Life on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diamond Jim’s Nevada Club Casino, a name synonymous with the electric energy of mid-century Las Vegas, occupied a small but significant space at 109 Fremont Street. While its existence was relatively brief, the club left an undeniable mark on the evolution of downtown Las Vegas and the burgeoning “Glitter Gulch” era. Today, the site is part of the Golden Nugget, but the memories of Diamond Jim’s remain vibrant, fueled by nostalgic collectors and historians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downtown Casino Center: Remembering Vintage Las Vegas’s Bold Branding Campaign</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/downtown-casino-center-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/downtown-casino-center-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-name-a-sign-and-a-destination-introducing-downtown-casino-center&#34;&gt;A Name, a Sign, and a Destination: Introducing Downtown Casino Center&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everyone recognizes the “Welcome to Fabulous Las Vegas” sign, but have you heard of Downtown Casino Center? In 1959, Las Vegas launched this ambitious branding campaign to solidify Fremont Street&amp;rsquo;s identity – and it wasn’t a single casino, but an entire district’s persona. The era was one of burgeoning competition, with the nascent Las Vegas Strip starting to pull attention away from the heart of Downtown. This campaign aimed to recapture that glory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Downtown Castaways Las Vegas: A Brief, Turbulent History | Vintage Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/downtown-castaways-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/downtown-castaways-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-showboat-to-castaways-a-name-change-and-a-rocky-start&#34;&gt;From Showboat to Castaways: A Name Change and a Rocky Start&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas has seen its share of transitions, but few were as fleeting and ultimately tragic as the story of the Castaways. It all began in 1998 when Harrah’s Entertainment acquired the Showboat Hotel and Casino. However, Harrah’s, needing to maintain the Showboat name for their Atlantic City property, quickly sold the downtown location just two years later. This sale, for $23.5 million, brought in VSS Enterprises, led by Dan Shaw, Mike Villamor, and Greg Schatzman, who were tasked with rebranding the property.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earl&#39;s Town Tavern: A Lost Jewel of Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/earls-town-tavern-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/earls-town-tavern-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-west-side-oasis-earls-town-taverns-story&#34;&gt;A West Side Oasis: Earl&amp;rsquo;s Town Tavern&amp;rsquo;s Story&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The history of Las Vegas is often painted with neon and glitz, but beneath the surface lies a complex story of segregation and resilience. Few places embody this duality more powerfully than Earl’s Town Tavern, a vital hub for the African American community on the West Side. Opening its doors on July 5, 1955, at 600 West Jackson Avenue, Earl’s Town Tavern wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a bar and casino; it was a lifeline. In a Las Vegas where Black patrons were routinely denied access to many entertainment venues, the Town Tavern offered a safe, lively, and culturally rich space.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eastside Cannery Casino Las Vegas: A Brief but Bright Chapter in Vintage Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/eastside-cannery-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/eastside-cannery-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-bold-vision-on-the-boulder-highway&#34;&gt;A Bold Vision on the Boulder Highway&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Eastside Cannery Casino and Hotel, rising on the Boulder Highway corridor, represented a bold move in Las Vegas’s evolving landscape. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t about competing with the Strip&amp;rsquo;s dazzling spectacle; instead, it aimed to deliver a full-service casino-hotel experience directly to the local community – a demographic often underserved in the boom years. Opening its doors on August 28, 2008, after a $250 million investment and demolishing the former Nevada Palace, the Cannery signaled an expansion of gaming beyond the core tourist zones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>El Rancho Vegas: The Birth of the Las Vegas Strip - A Vintage History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-rancho-hotel-and-casino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-rancho-hotel-and-casino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-dawn-of-the-strip-remembering-el-rancho-vegas&#34;&gt;The Dawn of the Strip: Remembering El Rancho Vegas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vintage Las Vegas conjures images of neon lights, big band music, and a sense of boundless possibility. And it all, arguably, began with El Rancho Hotel and Casino. Opened on April 3, 1941, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t just another hotel; it was the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; resort on what would become the famed Las Vegas Strip, then known as Highway 91 in Winchester, Nevada. Its impact on the development of Las Vegas is undeniable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Escape to Paradise: A Look Back at Don the Beachcomber Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/don-the-beachcomber-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/don-the-beachcomber-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-oasis-don-the-beachcomber-at-the-sahara&#34;&gt;A Desert Oasis: Don the Beachcomber at the Sahara&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mid-century Las Vegas Strip was a canvas for spectacle, and few experiences were as captivating as Don the Beachcomber at the Sahara Hotel. Opening its doors on December 1, 1962, this wasn’t just a restaurant; it was a full-blown immersive Polynesian escape. Imagine stepping off the casino floor and instantly being transported to a lush, tropical paradise – that was the magic of Don the Beachcomber.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farewell, Flamingo&#39;s Sister: A Look Back at the Tropicana Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tropicana-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas-verions-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tropicana-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas-verions-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-lush-oasis-arrives-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Lush Oasis Arrives on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Tropicana Hotel and Casino burst onto the Las Vegas scene on April 4, 1957, it was an instant spectacle. Built on 35 acres – a vast expanse for the time – it represented the most expensive resort in Las Vegas, boasting over 1,400 rooms and a sprawling 44,570 square foot casino. Its lush, tropical landscaping, evoking a South Seas paradise, was a deliberate departure from the more staid, traditional hotels that preceded it. The “Mermaid Lounge” fountain became an iconic symbol.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forgotten Glamour: The Pair A Dice Hotel &amp; Casino and the &#39;Bella Ladies&#39; of Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pair-a-dice-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas-bella-ladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pair-a-dice-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas-bella-ladies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-fleeting-star-on-north-las-vegas-boulevard&#34;&gt;A Fleeting Star on North Las Vegas Boulevard&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip we know today is a tapestry woven from the threads of countless dreams, some brilliant, some faded. Among those fleeting dreams was the Pair-A-Dice Hotel and Casino, a short-lived but intriguing player in the city’s burgeoning gambling scene. Launched in 1956 at 2067 North Las Vegas Boulevard (a location now vacant), the Pair-A-Dice represented the expansion of Vegas beyond the central Strip, catering to a broader clientele, many of whom were drawn to the promise of affordable lodging and entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Aqua to Shalimar: A Vintage Las Vegas Strip Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/aqua-hotel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/aqua-hotel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-humble-beginning-the-home-motel-and-a-fiery-start&#34;&gt;A Humble Beginning: The Home Motel and a Fiery Start&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The location at 1401 South Las Vegas Boulevard, now the Shalimar Hotel, boasts a layered history reflecting the evolving face of the Las Vegas Strip. Before the glitz and grandeur, it began as the Home Motel in the late 1930s – a modest auto-court catering to travelers passing through. This was a time when Las Vegas was still carving out its identity as a destination. Sadly, the Home Motel&amp;rsquo;s early years were marked by tragedy: a significant fire in October 1941 devastated the property. But Las Vegas is built on resilience, and from the ashes rose something new.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Casino to Community: The Story of Pair A Dice Trailer Park Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pair-a-dice-trailer-park-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pair-a-dice-trailer-park-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-dicey-start-the-pair-a-dice-casino-and-its-origins&#34;&gt;A Dicey Start: The Pair-A-Dice Casino and its Origins&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Long before the mega-resorts and the dazzling spectacle of the Las Vegas Strip, North Las Vegas was a different kind of frontier. In 1956, the Pair-A-Dice Club casino opened its doors at 2067 North Las Vegas Boulevard. While it never reached the heights of the downtown casinos or the later Strip behemoths, it was part of the burgeoning entertainment scene that helped define early Las Vegas. Like many establishments of the era, the Pair-A-Dice likely played a role in the city’s rapid expansion and the development of surrounding areas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From International Glamour to Westgate: A Look Back at the Las Vegas Hilton Hotel &amp; Casino</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/las-vegas-hilton-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/las-vegas-hilton-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rise-of-a-vegas-giant&#34;&gt;The Rise of a Vegas Giant&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Hilton. Just the name conjures up images of glitz, Elvis, and a bygone era of Las Vegas excess. But its story is far more complex than just shimmering lights and showstopping performances. Initially known as the International Hotel and Casino, it was the brainchild of Kirk Kerkorian, aiming to compete with the iconic Sahara and Flamingo. In 1970, Kerkorian began selling shares to Hilton Hotels, a pivotal moment that cemented the property&amp;rsquo;s destiny. The official renaming to Las Vegas Hilton in July 1971 signaled a new chapter and, ultimately, a dramatic shift in its fortunes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Maxim to Westin: A Look Back at the Casuarina Hotel and Casino Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/casuarina-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/casuarina-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-kid-on-the-strip-the-maxim-era&#34;&gt;A New Kid on the Strip: The Maxim Era&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before it became the Westin, and before that, the Casuarina, the property we know today was the Maxim Hotel and Casino. Opened in 1990, the Maxim was a bold attempt to capture a younger, more hip clientele – a move away from the traditional glitz and glamor of many Strip hotels. It was designed with a contemporary aesthetic and marketed aggressively, targeting a more casual visitor. While it never quite achieved the iconic status of its neighbors, it carved out a niche, especially during the early 90s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From MGM Grand to Bally’s: A Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/ballys-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/ballys-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-fiery-beginning-the-mgm-grand-era-1973-1980&#34;&gt;A Fiery Beginning: The MGM Grand Era (1973-1980)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bally’s Las Vegas, now Horseshoe, didn&amp;rsquo;t start as Bally’s at all. It began as the MGM Grand in 1973, a sprawling 2,100-room megaresort designed to impress. Its sheer size was a statement – a bold declaration that Las Vegas was serious about big. Think glittering chandeliers, a massive casino floor, and the iconic MGM lion statues proudly displayed everywhere. For a time, it was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to be. However, this era is tragically overshadowed by a devastating fire on November 21, 1980. The blaze, sparked by faulty electrical work, ripped through the casino and lower levels, claiming 85 lives and injuring hundreds. The event remains the deadliest single incident in Nevada&amp;rsquo;s history and fundamentally altered the safety standards for all Las Vegas casinos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Newsstand to Downtown Grand: A Look Back at the Lady Luck Hotel and Casino Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lady-luck-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lady-luck-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-lucky-start-from-honest-johns-to-lady-luck&#34;&gt;A Lucky Start: From Honest John&amp;rsquo;s to Lady Luck&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The corner of Fremont and Las Vegas Boulevard is a prime piece of real estate, and its history reflects the evolving fortunes of Las Vegas itself. Before the dazzling lights of the Downtown Grand shone brightly, this location was home to Honest John’s, a simple newsstand and barbershop. Can you imagine a bustling Strip starting with such unassuming roots? It’s a testament to how far Las Vegas has come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Saloon to License #1: The Fascinating History of the Northern Club Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/northern-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/northern-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-humble-beginnings-of-a-legend&#34;&gt;The Humble Beginnings of a Legend&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the dazzling lights of the Las Vegas Strip, there was Fremont Street, and at the heart of that early casino district stood the Northern Club. Its story is more than just about games of chance; it&amp;rsquo;s about the evolution of Las Vegas itself. The building’s roots stretch back to April 1, 1912, when it opened as “The Northern,” a saloon and hotel catering to the burgeoning rail-town. While gambling existed in Las Vegas prior to 1931, it operated in a legal gray area, often under the cloak of secrecy. This was particularly true during the Hoover Dam construction boom, which brought a massive influx of workers – and a corresponding demand for entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Golden Gate Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Vegas Time Capsule | Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/golden-gate-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/golden-gate-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-hotel-nevada-to-the-golden-gate-the-birth-of-vegas-hospitality&#34;&gt;From Hotel Nevada to the Golden Gate: The Birth of Vegas Hospitality&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas. The name conjures images of dazzling lights, high-stakes gambling, and world-class entertainment. But before the Strip, before the mega-resorts, there was the Golden Gate Hotel and Casino, standing proudly at the corner of Main Street and Fremont. Originally opening in 1906 as the humble Hotel Nevada, it wasn’t just a place to sleep; it was a beacon of modernity in a fledgling desert town fueled by the railroad. With just ten rooms, it offered unheard-of luxuries like electric lights and indoor plumbing – a stark contrast to the surrounding landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honest John’s Casino: A Blast From Vintage Las Vegas’s Past</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/honest-johns-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/honest-johns-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-strip-unlike-todays-the-north-strips-wild-past&#34;&gt;A Strip Unlike Today&amp;rsquo;s: The North Strip&amp;rsquo;s Wild Past&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today’s Las Vegas Strip is dominated by sprawling resorts and mega-casinos. But rewind to the 1960s and early 70s, and you&amp;rsquo;d find a different beast – a strip characterized by smaller, independently-owned properties, each vying for attention with unique concepts and, often, a healthy dose of personality. Among the most memorable of these was Honest John’s Casino, a vibrant and irreverent landmark that stood at 2440 Las Vegas Boulevard South, just north of Sahara.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Little Caesars Casino: A Forgotten Gem of Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/little-caesars-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/little-caesars-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-strip-anomaly-little-caesars-casino-not-the-pizza&#34;&gt;A Strip Anomaly: Little Caesars Casino (Not the Pizza!)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip we know today – a dazzling expanse of mega-resorts – wasn&amp;rsquo;t always so. Decades ago, it was a different beast, a place where small, quirky establishments carved out their own niches. Among those was Little Caesars Casino, a remarkably unique sportsbook-casino hybrid that operated from roughly 1970 to 1994, existing as a fascinating footnote in Las Vegas history. Don&amp;rsquo;t confuse it with the later national pizza chain; this Little Caesars was a distinctly Vegas creation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost &amp; Found: Remembering the Hotel Continental and Casino – A Vintage Las Vegas Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/hotel-continental-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/hotel-continental-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-bold-vision-on-paradise-road&#34;&gt;A Bold Vision on Paradise Road&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a brief but memorable period in the 1980s and 90s, the Hotel Continental and Casino stood as a distinct landmark on Paradise Road, just south of the burgeoning Las Vegas Strip. Built on a sprawling 10-acre parcel, construction began in 1979 and the property finally opened its doors in 1980. While the Strip was quickly becoming synonymous with mega-resorts, the Continental aimed to offer a slightly different experience, targeting a local clientele alongside tourists seeking something a little less overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost &amp; Found: Remembering the Short-Lived Riata Casino on the Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/riata-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/riata-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-brief-blaze-the-story-of-the-riata-casino&#34;&gt;A Brief Blaze: The Story of the Riata Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vintage Las Vegas is filled with tales of ambitious dreams and spectacular failures, and few stories are as concise and poignant as that of the Riata Casino. Opened in July 1973, this little-remembered casino occupied a prime location at 3001 Las Vegas Boulevard South – directly across from the iconic Stardust Hotel and Casino. Today, the site is the Silver City Plaza, but for a mere year, it was the Riata, a blink-and-you’ll-miss-it chapter in Strip history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost &amp; Found: The Forgotten History of Pair A Dice Hotel &amp; Casino in Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pair-a-dice-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pair-a-dice-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-dicey-beginning-the-pair-a-dice-arrives-1956&#34;&gt;A Dicey Beginning: The Pair-A-Dice Arrives (1956)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wasn&amp;rsquo;t always the glittering behemoth it is today. In the 1950s, development was spreading north along Las Vegas Boulevard, and a surprising number of smaller, independent casinos popped up. Among these was the Pair-A-Dice Hotel and Casino, which opened its doors in 1956 at 2067 North Las Vegas Boulevard. While not boasting the grandeur of the Flamingo or the Sands, the Pair-A-Dice represented a vital part of the burgeoning North Strip landscape. Information about its early ownership and specific features remains scarce – a testament to how quickly it faded from the collective Vegas memory – but it likely offered the typical fare of the era: slots, a small poker room, and a modest lounge. Its location, further north than the established &amp;ldquo;center&amp;rdquo; of the Strip, meant it catered to a slightly different clientele, perhaps those looking for a more relaxed, less pretentious gambling experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost &amp; Found: The Original Fortune Club Hotel and Casino – A Downtown Vegas Memory</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fortune-club-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fortune-club-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-glimpse-into-downtowns-golden-age&#34;&gt;A Glimpse into Downtown’s Golden Age&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and choreographed fountain shows, Downtown Las Vegas was a collection of intimate casinos, each vying for the attention of tourists and locals alike. Among them, from 1953 to 1958, stood the Fortune Club Hotel and Casino at 109 Fremont Street. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a glamorous landmark by today’s standards, but it represented a crucial period in the evolution of Las Vegas – a time of smaller stakes, independent operators, and a unique, gritty charm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost &amp; Found: The Story of the Apache Hotel Las Vegas – A Vintage Downtown Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/apache-hotel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/apache-hotel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-pioneer-on-fremont-street-the-birth-of-the-apache-hotel&#34;&gt;A Pioneer on Fremont Street: The Birth of the Apache Hotel&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the dazzling lights of the Las Vegas Strip, there was Fremont Street, and nestled within that burgeoning downtown scene stood the Hotel Apache. Opened on March 19, 1932, a time of immense economic hardship, the Apache wasn&amp;rsquo;t just another hotel – it was an ambitious statement of hope and luxury. The Silvagni family poured their resources into creating something special, a refuge for travelers and a social hub for Las Vegas locals. With 81 rooms, it represented a significant investment in a city still finding its footing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Legends of Fremont Street: Remembering the Eldorado Club Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/eldorado-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/eldorado-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-frontier-welcome-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Frontier Welcome on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and the Fremont Street Experience, downtown Las Vegas was a different beast – a collection of independent gambling halls carving out their identities along Fremont Street. Among these early pioneers was the Eldorado Club, a beloved fixture at 128 Fremont Street from 1947 to 1951. Situated strategically next to the Boulder Club and across from the burgeoning casino row, the Eldorado embodied the Wild West theme that was so prevalent in postwar Las Vegas. Its signage, evocative of a frontier outpost, promised friendly gaming “just off the trail,” a welcome to travelers and locals alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Oasis: Remembering Mecca Slots Casino – A Vintage Las Vegas Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mecca-slots-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mecca-slots-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-brief-bloom-in-the-desert-mecca-slots-casino&#34;&gt;A Brief Bloom in the Desert: Mecca Slots Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas history is brimming with tales of extravagance and innovation, but sometimes it’s the smaller, quieter stories that truly capture the spirit of the era. Take Mecca Slots Casino, for example. A blink-and-you-missed-it establishment that operated for a mere six months, from July 1st to December 31st, 1973, it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating snapshot of a transitional period in Vegas gaming. Located off the bustling Strip, on Fremont Street, Mecca Slots represented a different kind of Vegas – one geared towards locals and value-conscious tourists seeking a more relaxed atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Oasis: Remembering the Algiers Hotel and Casino – A Vintage Las Vegas Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/algiers-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/algiers-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-mirage-the-algiers-arrives&#34;&gt;A Desert Mirage: The Algiers Arrives&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wasn&amp;rsquo;t always about mega-resorts and choreographed fountain shows. In the 1950s, it was a landscape of emerging casinos, each vying for attention with its own distinct character. Among these pioneers was the Algiers Hotel and Casino, a whimsical Arabian-themed escape that opened its doors on November 25, 1953. Located at 2845 South Las Vegas Boulevard – a prime spot now occupied by the Fontainebleau – the Algiers was more than just a hotel; it was a themed experience, a departure from the prevailing Western and modern aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Oasis: Remembering the Algiers Hotel and Casino – A Vintage Las Vegas Treasure</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/algiers-hotel-and-casino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/algiers-hotel-and-casino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-mirage-the-algiers-hotels-grand-opening&#34;&gt;A Desert Mirage: The Algiers Hotel&amp;rsquo;s Grand Opening&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip in the 1950s was a landscape of burgeoning dreams and bold architectural statements. Amidst the burgeoning neon, the Algiers Hotel and Casino, opening on November 25, 1953, stood out as a particularly enchanting creation. Designed with a striking Arabian and Persian theme, the hotel offered a unique escape for visitors, a far cry from the Western saloons and dusty landscapes often associated with Nevada. Located at 2845 South Las Vegas Boulevard, it was strategically positioned as a sister property to the popular Thunderbird Hotel and Casino, capitalizing on the growing popularity of the Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Oasis: Remembering the Casbah Hotel and Casino on the Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/casbah-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/casbah-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-moroccan-dream-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Moroccan Dream on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen its share of transformations, but few stories are as complex and ultimately tragic as that of the Casbah Hotel and Casino. Built in 1963 by the ambitious Danny Jackson, the Casbah aimed to transport visitors to a Moroccan paradise. Its architecture, rich with vibrant colors, intricate tilework, and lush landscaping, stood out even amidst the burgeoning glitz of the early 1960s Strip. It offered a unique aesthetic departure from the standard modern designs, promising an exotic escape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Oasis: Remembering the Greek Isles Hotel and Casino – A Vintage Vegas Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/greek-isles-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/greek-isles-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-land-of-reincarnation-the-sites-colorful-past&#34;&gt;A Land of Reincarnation: The Site&amp;rsquo;s Colorful Past&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 305 Convention Center Drive address in Las Vegas has seen more transformations than a chameleon. Before the Greek Isles Hotel and Casino graced its footprint, it was home to the Debbie Reynolds Hollywood Hotel, a tribute to the iconic actress&amp;rsquo;s career. Before &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;? A Howard Johnson’s Motor Lodge! This constant state of flux reflects the ever-evolving nature of Las Vegas itself, a city built on reinvention. The location’s proximity to the Convention Center ensured it remained a crucial, albeit sometimes overlooked, piece of the puzzle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Oasis: Remembering the Original Aladdin Hotel &amp; Casino Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/aladdin-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/aladdin-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-curious-beginning-from-tallyho-to-kings-crown&#34;&gt;A Curious Beginning: From Tallyho to King’s Crown&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before shimmering silks, Arabian Nights decor, and Elvis nuptials, the location now occupied by Planet Hollywood on the Las Vegas Strip was something entirely different. In 1962, toy magnate Edwin S. Lowe, known for his novelty toys, opened the Tallyho Hotel. Picture this: an English Tudor-style resort, jarringly out of place amongst the burgeoning glitz of the Strip, with 450 rooms but…no casino. Lowe’s bold experiment of a non-gaming hotel proved unsustainable, and within a year, the Tallyho closed its doors, burdened by financial difficulties. A brief resurrection followed in 1963 as the King’s Crown Tallyho, but plans for a casino were repeatedly blocked by the Nevada Gaming Control Board due to concerns about financing – highlighting the importance of gaming licenses in the burgeoning Vegas landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Oasis: Remembering the Vintage Aladdin Hotel and Casino on the Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/aladdin-hotel-and-casino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/aladdin-hotel-and-casino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;remembering-the-magic-of-the-aladdin-hotel-and-casino&#34;&gt;Remembering the Magic of the Aladdin Hotel and Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen countless transformations over the decades, but few disappearances were as dramatic as the original Aladdin Hotel and Casino. Opening its doors at midnight on April 1, 1966, at 3667 South Las Vegas Blvd, the Aladdin wasn’t just another casino; it was a full-fledged theatrical experience transported to the desert.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-arabian-dream&#34;&gt;A Desert Arabian Dream&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Aladdin&amp;rsquo;s theme was instantly striking: an opulent, Arabesque design. Lush carpets, towering brass lamps, and elaborate mosaics transported guests to a fantastical Middle Eastern world. The centerpiece was a massive, working stagecoach that would dramatically descend from the hotel&amp;rsquo;s façade, carrying guests down a miniature “desert” landscape into the casino. This elaborate spectacle was a major draw and a quintessential element of the 1960s Vegas showmanship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Oasis: The Rise and Fall of the Landmark Hotel and Casino - Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/landmark-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/landmark-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-dream-deferred-the-story-of-the-landmark-hotel-and-casino&#34;&gt;A Dream Deferred: The Story of the Landmark Hotel and Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of us who cherish vintage Las Vegas, the memory of the Landmark Hotel and Casino represents a bittersweet chapter. Located just off the Strip, in what is now Winchester, Nevada, the Landmark’s story is one of big ambitions, frustrating delays, and ultimately, a failure to thrive in an increasingly competitive landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-caroll-era--early-challenges-1961-1968&#34;&gt;The Caroll Era &amp;amp; Early Challenges (1961-1968)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Frank Caroll, a familiar name in early Vegas gaming, envisioned a grand resort in 1961. He purchased the land and quickly began construction, initially focusing on a shopping center and apartments which opened by the end of 1961. A towering hotel-casino was next, construction beginning in September of the same year. Initial progress was promising, with around 80% of the tower taking shape by 1962. However, funding proved to be a major hurdle, bringing construction to a standstill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Oasis: The Story of Tropicana Country Club – A Vintage Las Vegas Dream</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tropicana-country-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tropicana-country-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-different-vision-for-las-vegas-enter-the-tropicana-country-club&#34;&gt;A Different Vision for Las Vegas: Enter the Tropicana Country Club&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip is synonymous with glitz, glamour, and late-night revelry. But rewind to the 1950s, and you’ll find a Las Vegas trying to define itself. Beyond the casinos, a quieter vision emerged – a place where professionals, families, and even casino executives could put down roots. This ambition materialized as the Tropicana Country Club, a planned residential and leisure community east of the Strip, near what is now Tropicana Avenue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Paradise: A Look Back at the Castaways Hotel &amp; Casino - Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/castaways-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/castaways-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-fleeting-escape-remembering-the-castaways-hotel--casino&#34;&gt;A Fleeting Escape: Remembering the Castaways Hotel &amp;amp; Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen countless resorts rise and fall, each leaving its mark on the city&amp;rsquo;s evolving identity. Among those, the Castaways Hotel and Casino holds a unique place – a short-lived Polynesian fantasy that paved the way for one of the Strip’s most iconic mega-resorts, The Mirage.  Its story is a microcosm of the rapid growth and constant reinvention that defines Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Paradise: A Look Back at the Castaways Hotel &amp; Casino - Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/castaways-hotel-and-casino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/castaways-hotel-and-casino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-but-bright-polynesian-dream-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Brief but Bright Polynesian Dream on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of us who cherish vintage Las Vegas, the Castaways Hotel &amp;amp; Casino holds a bittersweet place in memory. Standing on the Strip today, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine a resort once occupied that space, but from 1963 to 1987, the Castaways offered a distinct Polynesian flair amidst a rapidly evolving landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story begins with the Sans Souci, a struggling property bought by Ben Jaffe, already a prominent figure due to his ownership of the Tropicana. Recognizing potential, Jaffe ambitiously rebranded it as the Castaways, promising a vibrant Polynesian-themed escape. The September 1, 1963, reopening was a genuine attempt to offer something different – tiki torches, lush landscaping, and a casino run by the experienced duo of Ike P. LaRue and Everett Eugene McCarlie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Paradise: Remembering Aku Aku Polynesian Restaurant in Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/aku-aku-polynesian-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/aku-aku-polynesian-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-tropical-oasis-on-the-strip-introducing-aku-aku&#34;&gt;A Tropical Oasis on the Strip: Introducing Aku Aku&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been about spectacle and escaping reality, but few experiences embodied that ethos as perfectly as Aku Aku Polynesian Restaurant. Opening its doors on January 29, 1960, inside the Stardust Resort &amp;amp; Casino, Aku Aku wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a restaurant; it was an immersive Polynesian fantasy. In an era where diners expected formality and predictability, Aku Aku offered a bold and exciting alternative – a complete transportation to a South Pacific paradise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Paradise: Remembering Mermaids Casino, A Vintage Fremont Street Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mermaids-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mermaids-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-little-slice-of-island-life-in-downtown-vegas&#34;&gt;A Little Slice of Island Life in Downtown Vegas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For years, a little slice of tropical escape existed right on Fremont Street: Mermaids Casino. Though now gone, replaced by the impressive Circa Resort &amp;amp; Casino, Mermaids left a lasting impression on those who frequented downtown Las Vegas. Its story is a microcosm of the area&amp;rsquo;s evolution – a tale of small-scale charm swallowed by big-time development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-silver-palace-to-sassy-sallys-a-building-with-a-past&#34;&gt;From Silver Palace to Sassy Sally&amp;rsquo;s: A Building with a Past&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But Mermaids wasn&amp;rsquo;t always Mermaids. The building at 32 East Fremont Street had a long and varied history, dating back to 1956 when it debuted as the Silver Palace. This was a significant moment for Vegas, as the Silver Palace was one of the first casinos to feature two levels, a design novelty accentuated by Southern Nevada&amp;rsquo;s first escalator! Over the decades, it wore many faces, including Carousel, Gambler&amp;rsquo;s Hall of Fame, Sundance West, and Sassy Sally&amp;rsquo;s – each attempting to capture the era&amp;rsquo;s vibe. The constant rebranding reflects the ever-changing tastes of Vegas visitors and the desire for casino owners to find that elusive winning formula.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Paradise: Remembering the Algiers Hotel and Casino – A Vintage Las Vegas Treasure</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/algiers-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/algiers-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-night-in-the-arabian-desert-just-off-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Night in the Arabian Desert, Just Off the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of us who cherish the memory of vintage Las Vegas, the Algiers Hotel and Casino holds a special place. Opened on November 25, 1953, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t just another casino; it was an immersive experience. Located at 2845 South Las Vegas Boulevard, its distinct Arabian/Persian theme – complete with elaborate architecture, costumed staff, and exotic décor – immediately set it apart from its contemporaries. It stood as a sister property to the iconic Thunderbird Hotel and Casino, reflecting the early ambition to create themed resorts along the burgeoning Las Vegas Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Paradise: Remembering the Castaways Hotel &amp; Casino – A Vintage Las Vegas Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/castaways-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/castaways-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-tropical-escape-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Brief Tropical Escape on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and the dazzling spectacle that defines modern Las Vegas, there were properties like the Castaways Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, each with its own unique story. Tucked away on the Strip, the Castaways, born from the ashes of the financially troubled Sans Souci in 1963, offered a fleeting taste of Polynesian paradise to weary travelers. Ben Jaffe, a prominent Las Vegas investor and then-owner of the Tropicana, acquired the Sans Souci and immediately envisioned a transformation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Paradise: Remembering the Legendary Congo Room Restaurant in Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/congo-room-restaurant-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/congo-room-restaurant-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-jungle-of-glamour-the-congo-rooms-rise-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Jungle of Glamour: The Congo Room&amp;rsquo;s Rise on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen countless transformations, but few venues evoke the nostalgic grandeur of the Congo Room Restaurant at the Sahara Hotel and Casino. Opening shortly after the Sahara debuted in 1952, the Congo Room wasn’t just a restaurant; it was a complete experience – a supper club blending fine dining with top-tier entertainment, perfectly encapsulating the burgeoning glamour of mid-century Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Paradise: Remembering the Polynesian Hotel and Casino in Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/polynesian-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/polynesian-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-tropical-dream-on-tropicana-the-polynesians-brief-reign&#34;&gt;A Tropical Dream on Tropicana: The Polynesian&amp;rsquo;s Brief Reign&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 1980s and early 90s in Las Vegas were a period of intense experimentation. The Strip was exploding with mega-resorts, but smaller properties on the periphery, like those along Tropicana Avenue, fought to find their niche. Enter the Polynesian Hotel and Casino, a bold attempt to transport visitors to a South Pacific paradise, albeit on a modest scale. Opened in 1985, it occupied the spot at 115 East Tropicana, a location previously home to a Howard Johnson’s Motor Lodge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Paradise: Remembering the Short-Lived Paradise Hotel &amp; Casino Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/paradise-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/paradise-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-fleeting-taste-of-paradise-on-tropicana-avenue&#34;&gt;A Fleeting Taste of Paradise on Tropicana Avenue&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of us who love digging into the layers of Las Vegas history, there are stories of titans like Bugsy Siegel and Howard Hughes. But then there are the smaller, often forgotten ventures – the ambitious dreams that flickered brightly, then faded too soon. The Paradise Hotel and Casino is one such story, a curious blip on the timeline of the Las Vegas Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost to Time: Remembering the Orbit Inn, a Vintage Las Vegas Space-Age Dream</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/orbit-inn-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/orbit-inn-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-blast-from-the-past-the-orbit-inns-rise&#34;&gt;A Blast From the Past: The Orbit Inn&amp;rsquo;s Rise&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Fremont Street Experience is buzzing with life today, a vibrant hub of shops, restaurants, and entertainment. But if you squint, and really remember, you might picture something very different – a slice of vintage Las Vegas, shimmering with space-age optimism. That was the Orbit Inn, a roadside motel that, for a brief but brilliant time, defined a particular aesthetic of the “Late American Rich,” as captured by Tom Wolfe’s writings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Treasures &amp; Dragon Roofs: Remembering the Imperial Palace Hotel &amp; Casino&#39;s Unique V Neck Era in Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/imperial-palace-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas-v-neck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/imperial-palace-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas-v-neck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-palace-rises-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Palace Rises on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For decades, the Imperial Palace Hotel and Casino stood as a distinct landmark on the Las Vegas Strip. Its journey began far more humbly as the Flamingo Capri motel, but a visionary purchase by Ralph Engelstad in the early 1970s set it on a path to becoming a uniquely themed destination. Engelstad’s concept, realized through the design talents of Merlin J. Barth, wasn&amp;rsquo;t just about creating a casino; it was about transporting guests to an imagined ancient Chinese palace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Under the Sea: Remembering the Dome of the Sea Restaurant in Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dome-of-the-sea-restaurant-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dome-of-the-sea-restaurant-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-submerged-spectacle-the-dome-of-the-sea-at-the-dunes-hotel&#34;&gt;A Submerged Spectacle: The Dome of the Sea at the Dunes Hotel&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas in the 1960s wasn&amp;rsquo;t just about gambling; it was a race to deliver unparalleled entertainment and experiences. Among the most ambitious – and unforgettable – of these was the Dome of the Sea, a seafood restaurant at the Dunes Hotel that truly transported diners to another world. Opened on June 12, 1965, as part of the hotel’s significant expansion and modernization led by architect Milton M. Schwartz, it remains a beloved memory for those who witnessed its magic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering Cosmo’s Underground – A Downtown Dining Secret</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/cosmos-underground-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/cosmos-underground-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;descending-into-delight-the-cosmos-underground-era&#34;&gt;Descending into Delight: The Cosmo’s Underground Era&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip gets all the glory, but true vintage Vegas aficionados know the heart of the city beat strongest downtown, especially during the mid-century years. And tucked beneath the glitz and clamor of Fremont Street, a little gem shone: Cosmo’s Underground Restaurant. More than just a place to eat, it was a &lt;em&gt;vibe&lt;/em&gt;. Located below the iconic (and now sadly gone) Sassy Sally’s casino, it offered an escape from the neon glare above – a retreat into a world of low ceilings, intimate lighting, and an atmosphere unlike anything else in town.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering Pigalle Discotheque and Casino - A 1970s Flash on the Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pigalle-discotheque-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pigalle-discotheque-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-parisian-spark-on-the-las-vegas-strip-pigalle-discotheque--casino&#34;&gt;A Parisian Spark on the Las Vegas Strip: Pigalle Discotheque &amp;amp; Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been about reinvention. But some eras represent particularly dramatic shifts. The mid-1970s were one such time, and nestled amongst the familiar neon and casino sparkle was a club that stood apart: Pigalle Discotheque and Casino. Its story, though short, provides a fascinating glimpse into a fleeting moment in Las Vegas history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rise-of-pigalle-a-daring-concept&#34;&gt;The Rise of Pigalle: A Daring Concept&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around 1974, Pigalle boldly took over a prime corner location on the Strip, specifically at Sands Avenue (now Las Vegas Boulevard South). Situated right beside the Rose Bowl Race Book, and soon followed by the famously flamboyant Dirty Sally’s, Pigalle’s arrival was visually striking. The name itself was a statement, a deliberate nod to the Parisian Pigalle district, renowned for its cabarets and a certain &lt;em&gt;je ne sais quoi&lt;/em&gt; – a touch of bohemian flair and, let’s be honest, a reputation for risqué entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the Barrel House Bar – A Fremont Street Pioneer</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/barrel-house-bar-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/barrel-house-bar-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-humble-beginning-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Humble Beginning on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the dazzling lights and mega-resorts, Fremont Street was the heart of Las Vegas. And nestled within that early entertainment hub was a little-known but significant establishment: the Barrel House Bar. Opening its doors on October 6, 1934, it stood in a prime location, a bit tucked away in the alley between the Las Vegas Club and the iconic Golden Goose sign. Today, that spot is part of the bustling Fremont Street Experience, but back then, it was a vital piece of the downtown landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the Cinnabar Cocktail Lounge – A Downtown Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/cinnabar-cocktail-lounge-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/cinnabar-cocktail-lounge-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-taste-of-the-old-west-in-the-desert-bloom&#34;&gt;A Taste of the Old West in the Desert Bloom&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas’s history isn’t just about glittering casinos and high rollers. It&amp;rsquo;s about the humble beginnings, the local watering holes, and the unique characters that shaped the city’s identity. One such place, though now lost to time and development, was the Cinnabar Cocktail Lounge. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t a sprawling resort; it was a beloved, “Truly Western” saloon nestled in the heart of downtown Las Vegas during its pivotal post-war boom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the El Morocco Motel and Casino – A Strip Icon</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-morocco-motel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-morocco-motel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-slice-of-mid-century-strip-charm-the-el-moroccos-debut&#34;&gt;A Slice of Mid-Century Strip Charm: The El Morocco&amp;rsquo;s Debut&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Between the iconic La Concha Motel and the ever-glamorous Peppermill Restaurant, a lesser-remembered gem once sparkled on the Las Vegas Strip: the El Morocco Motel and Casino. Opening its doors in 1964, it represented a new kind of convenience and style, a hallmark of the burgeoning Las Vegas experience. Owned by Lorenzo Doumani, the same visionary behind the La Concha, the El Morocco’s design owed a distinct debt to the brilliant architect Paul Revere Williams. Like its sister property, it epitomized the Googie architectural aesthetic – all sharp angles, swooping curves, and a futuristic, optimistic vibe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the Elwell Hotel and Casino - A Vintage Strip Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/elwell-hotel-and-casino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/elwell-hotel-and-casino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;remembering-a-piece-of-old-vegas-the-elwell-hotel-and-casino&#34;&gt;Remembering a Piece of Old Vegas: The Elwell Hotel and Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip we know today is a landscape of constant evolution. Grand resorts rise, and even older establishments fall to make way for new ventures. Among the vanished landmarks, the Elwell Hotel and Casino holds a special place, representing an early chapter in Las Vegas’s remarkable story. Located at First and Carson Streets (now beneath a Golden Nugget parking garage), the Elwell wasn&amp;rsquo;t a sprawling resort, but a vital part of the city’s burgeoning hospitality scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the Elwell Hotel and Casino – A Downtown Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/elwell-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/elwell-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-familys-legacy-in-the-desert-bloom&#34;&gt;A Family&amp;rsquo;s Legacy in the Desert Bloom&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling lights of the Las Vegas Strip dominated the skyline, Downtown Las Vegas thrived on a more intimate, family-run vibe. Tucked away at First and Carson Streets, a spot now occupied by a Golden Nugget parking garage, stood a building with a rich history: the Elwell Hotel. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t just another hotel; it was a testament to the perseverance of one of Las Vegas&amp;rsquo;s earliest families.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the Elwell Hotel and Casino – A Downtown Original</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/elwell-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/elwell-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-family-legacy-on-first-street&#34;&gt;A Family Legacy on First Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling lights of the Strip dominated the Las Vegas landscape, downtown was the heart and soul of the city&amp;rsquo;s burgeoning tourism scene. Nestled at the corner of First Street and Carson Avenue, a location now marked by a Golden Nugget parking garage, stood the Elwell Hotel, a testament to early Las Vegas family enterprise and a vital part of the city’s early growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the Flamingo Capri Hotel &amp; Casino – A Strip Evolution</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/flamingo-capri-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/flamingo-capri-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-stylish-start-the-flamingo-capris-debut-1959&#34;&gt;A Stylish Start: The Flamingo Capri&amp;rsquo;s Debut (1959)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip in 1959 was a landscape still finding its footing. While the Flamingo, built by Bugsy Siegel, had already established a precedent for lavish entertainment, smaller, stylish motels began to pepper the area, catering to a growing audience. Enter the Flamingo Capri, a 180-room motel erected just beside its namesake. George E. Goldberg and Bill Capri – the latter lending his name to the property – envisioned a modern, comfortable retreat, distinct from the more established casinos. It opened its doors in October 1959, promising a taste of understated elegance. The Capri was designed to be accessible, a step below the full-blown casino experience, offering a more relaxed alternative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the Kit Carson Motel – A Classic Strip Landmark</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/kit-carson-motel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/kit-carson-motel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-roadside-oasis-the-kit-carson-motel-emerges&#34;&gt;A Roadside Oasis: The Kit Carson Motel Emerges&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts, before the choreographed water shows and indoor canals, Las Vegas Boulevard was a different beast – a stretch of U.S. 91 catering to travelers making their way across the American West. Amongst those stops, nestled between the Last Frontier and the Flamingo, stood the Kit Carson Motel, a vibrant symbol of post-war leisure and the burgeoning Las Vegas Strip. Its story, like so many early Strip landmarks, is one of transition, ambition, and ultimately, loss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the Lucky Casino – A Fremont Street Flash in the Neon Era</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lucky-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lucky-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-bright-spark-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Brief, Bright Spark on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas in the early 1960s was a vibrant, competitive scene. While the Strip was beginning its ascent, Fremont Street remained the heart of gaming and entertainment. Into this bustling landscape stepped the Lucky Casino, opening its doors on May 6, 1963. It wasn’t just another casino; it was a statement. Built on the site of the former Lucky Strike Club after a significant four-month renovation, the Lucky Casino aimed to capture the energy of the burgeoning downtown gaming scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the Monaco Hotel and Casino – A Royal Connection on the Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/monaco-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/monaco-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-reign-the-monaco-motel-and-its-royal-suite&#34;&gt;A Brief Reign: The Monaco Motel (and its Royal Suite)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few Las Vegas properties are as fleetingly remembered as the Monaco Motel, located at 3073 South Las Vegas Boulevard. While it wasn&amp;rsquo;t one of the glamorous, headline-grabbing casinos on the main Strip, its story, however brief, offers a glimpse into the burgeoning motel landscape of the late 1950s and early 1990s. It opened its doors in 1958, a time when South Las Vegas Boulevard was still developing and the city&amp;rsquo;s tourism industry was rapidly expanding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the Quirky Keyhole Bar on Fremont Street</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/keyhole-bar-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/keyhole-bar-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-tiny-bar-a-big-impression-the-keyhole-bars-short-reign&#34;&gt;A Tiny Bar, a Big Impression: The Keyhole Bar’s Short Reign&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas’ Fremont Street Experience is a spectacle today, but rewind to the 1950s, and it was a different world – a more intimate, gritty, and delightfully eccentric place. Nestled between the burgeoning casinos, tiny bars like the Keyhole Bar thrived. Operating briefly from roughly 1953 to 1955, the Keyhole Bar, located at 13 Fremont Street within the Sal Sagev Hotel (later part of the Golden Gate), represents a crucial, often overlooked, chapter in Las Vegas history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering the Rendezvous Hotel &amp; Casino – A Downtown Flash in the Pan</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/rendezvous-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/rendezvous-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-encounter-the-rendezvous-hotel-and-casino&#34;&gt;A Brief Encounter: The Rendezvous Hotel and Casino&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas in the late 1970s was a whirlwind of change. The glitz and glamour of the burgeoning Las Vegas Strip was drawing visitors away, leaving Fremont Street facing increasing competition. Amidst this turbulence, smaller casinos fought to survive, constantly rebranding and experimenting to lure in gamblers. One such attempt, though ultimately brief, was the Rendezvous Hotel and Casino, located at 400 E. Ogden Avenue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: Remembering The Westerner Hotel and Casino - A Fremont Street Flashback</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-westerner-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-westerner-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-blaze-on-fremont-street-the-westerners-story&#34;&gt;A Brief Blaze on Fremont Street: The Westerner&amp;rsquo;s Story&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling lights of the Strip, Fremont Street was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to be in Las Vegas. And tucked amongst the bustling saloons and casinos of that era was a short-lived but memorable establishment: The Westerner Hotel and Casino. Opened on May 6, 1950, by the legendary Texas gambler Benny Binion, The Westerner occupied the location that&amp;rsquo;s now home to an ABC store at 23 Fremont Street - the site where the Las Vegas Club once stood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: The Monte Carlo Club – A Pioneer on Fremont Street</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/monte-carlo-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/monte-carlo-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-humble-beginning-in-downtowns-transformation&#34;&gt;A Humble Beginning in Downtown&amp;rsquo;s Transformation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the sprawling Las Vegas Strip we know today, there was Fremont Street. And before the Desert Inn redefined the luxury casino experience, there was Wilbur Clark and the Monte Carlo Club. Located at 15 Fremont Street, the Monte Carlo Club occupies a surprisingly significant, though often overlooked, place in Las Vegas history. It’s a story of transition, innovation, and the seeds of a gaming empire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lost Vegas: The Original Fortune Club Casino – A Downtown Gem Vanished</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fortune-club-hoet-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fortune-club-hoet-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-fleeting-fortune-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Fleeting Fortune on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and themed hotels dominated the Las Vegas landscape, Downtown reigned supreme. Among the bustling establishments of Fremont Street in the 1950s was the Fortune Club, a short-lived but notable casino offering a glimpse into a different era of Las Vegas. Located at 109 Fremont Street, it operated from 1953 to 1958, becoming just another piece of the puzzle that would become the entertainment capital of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Louigi’s Downtown: A Vintage Vegas Dining Gem Lost to Time</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/louigis-downtown-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/louigis-downtown-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-comfortable-haven-on-fremont-street-introducing-louigis&#34;&gt;A Comfortable Haven on Fremont Street: Introducing Louigi’s&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we think of vintage Las Vegas, visions of dazzling showrooms and high-roller extravagance often come to mind. But beneath the glitz and glamour of the Strip, Downtown Las Vegas held its own unique charm – and integral to that charm were establishments like Louigi’s. Nestled within the Silver Palace Casino on Fremont Street, Louigi’s was far more than just a restaurant; it was a refuge, a community hub, and a testament to a more approachable, comfortable era of Vegas hospitality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miss Lucy’s Casino: A Fleeting Flash of Vintage Vegas Charm</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/miss-lucys-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/miss-lucys-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-glimpse-of-americana-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Glimpse of Americana on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas in the mid-1990s was a fascinating tapestry of reinvention. While the Strip was pursuing mega-resorts and themed experiences, the Fremont Street Experience was just finding its footing, and a wave of smaller, character-driven casinos and bars were carving out their own niches. Among these fleeting establishments was Miss Lucy’s Gambling Hall &amp;amp; Saloon, a place that, despite its short lifespan, has become a beloved memory for vintage Las Vegas enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Sy&#39;s Casino: A Quirky Slice of Vintage Las Vegas &amp; That Iconic &#39;Bella Ladies V Neck&#39;!</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mr-sys-casino-las-vegas-bella-ladies-v-neck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mr-sys-casino-las-vegas-bella-ladies-v-neck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;remembering-mr-sys-more-than-just-slots--snacks&#34;&gt;Remembering Mr. Sy’s: More Than Just Slots &amp;amp; Snacks&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas has always been about spectacle, but sometimes the most memorable moments come from the unexpected. Mr. Sy’s Casino, a beloved and now-vanished institution, embodies exactly that. Tucked just off the Las Vegas Strip, across from the legendary Stardust, Mr. Sy&amp;rsquo;s wasn&amp;rsquo;t about high-roller tables or lavish suites. It was a quirky, character-driven casino that perfectly captured the spirit of old-school Las Vegas – a far cry from today’s mega-resorts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pussycat A Go Go Las Vegas: A Wild Ride Through Vintage Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pussycat-a-go-go-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pussycat-a-go-go-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dawn-of-a-new-vegas-vibe-pussycat-a-go-go&#34;&gt;The Dawn of a New Vegas Vibe: Pussycat A Go Go&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wasn&amp;rsquo;t always about high-roller casinos and choreographed fountain shows. In the mid-1960s, it was undergoing a cultural metamorphosis, transitioning from the Rat Pack’s sophisticated supper clubs to something raw, energetic, and decidedly more rebellious. Enter Pussycat A Go Go, a club that perfectly embodied this seismic shift. Opened in 1964, this legendary hotspot, now sadly beneath the sprawling Wynn Resort, remains a crucial piece of vintage Las Vegas history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember Davy? A Look Back at Davys Locker Bar and Casino, Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/davys-locker-bar-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/davys-locker-bar-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-slice-of-vegas-dive-life-davys-locker-bar-and-casino&#34;&gt;A Slice of Vegas Dive Life: Davys Locker Bar and Casino&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those who knew it, Davys Locker was more than just a bar; it was a refuge. Tucked away at the corner of Desert Inn Road and Maryland Parkway, just a stone&amp;rsquo;s throw from the dazzling lights of the Las Vegas Strip, Davys Locker opened its doors in 1968. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t one of the glittering casinos vying for high-roller attention, but a humble dive bar, a place where regulars and tourists could mingle over cheap drinks and a friendly game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember Foxy Dog Las Vegas? A Downtown Delight and Vintage Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/foxy-dog-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/foxy-dog-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-downtown-bite-and-a-little-bit-of-luck-remembering-foxy-dog-las-vegas&#34;&gt;A Downtown Bite and a Little Bit of Luck: Remembering Foxy Dog Las Vegas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas in the 1960s and 70s was a vibrant, chaotic, and undeniably &lt;em&gt;local&lt;/em&gt; experience. Forget the mega-resorts – the heart of the action beat on Fremont Street, fueled by neon, cheap eats, and the ever-present clang of slot machines. And nestled among the pioneers was a small, but memorable, establishment: Foxy Dog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-than-just-a-hot-dog-stand&#34;&gt;More Than Just a Hot Dog Stand&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Located at 326 Fremont Street, Foxy Dog wasn’t your average vendor. Owned by Abe and Evelyn Fox, the same folks behind Foxy’s Deli and Restaurant on the Strip, it was an experiment in blending classic diner fare with low-key gambling. The Foxes clearly understood the Fremont Street vibe; they sought to create a place where locals (and tourists seeking a more authentic experience) could grab a quick bite and try their luck.  They applied for, and received, a gaming license in 1964, allowing for 18 slot machines to operate alongside the hot dog counter.  A 1964 &lt;em&gt;Las Vegas Sun&lt;/em&gt; article playfully dubbed it “the hottest dog in town,” placing it right beside the popular Trader Bill&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember MGM Grand Adventures? A Look Back at Vegas&#39;s Ambitious Theme Park</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mgm-grand-adventures-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mgm-grand-adventures-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-the-blackjack-the-mgm-grand-adventures-dream&#34;&gt;Beyond the Blackjack: The MGM Grand Adventures Dream&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip. We think of glittering casinos, world-class shows, and high-rolling excitement. But did you know, for a brief but vibrant period, the Strip hosted something a little different: a theme park? MGM Grand Adventures, launched on December 18, 1993, was a bold attempt to expand Las Vegas’s appeal beyond the gambling crowd, targeting families and injecting a dose of Disney-esque fun into the desert landscape.  Built atop the former Tropicana golf course and originally spanning 33 acres, it was an audacious undertaking for MGM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember Pink E’s? A Vintage Vegas Pool Hall &amp; Entertainment Palace</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pink-es-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pink-es-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-blast-of-pink-introducing-pink-es&#34;&gt;A Blast of Pink: Introducing Pink E’s&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas history isn&amp;rsquo;t just about the Strip&amp;rsquo;s glittering casinos. It’s about the places that thrived just beyond the lights, creating their own unique communities and moments. One such place was Pink E’s Fun Food &amp;amp; Spirits, a sprawling entertainment complex that popped up in 1995 on West Flamingo Road, directly across from the Rio. This wasn’t your average pool hall; it was a full-blown experience, and a beloved fixture for nearly a decade.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember Splash Las Vegas? A Deep Dive into the Riviera&#39;s Aquatic Spectacle | Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/splash-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/splash-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-cascade-of-memories-remembering-splash-las-vegas&#34;&gt;A Cascade of Memories: Remembering Splash Las Vegas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been a place of spectacle, but few productions managed to capture the era quite like &lt;em&gt;Splash&lt;/em&gt; at the Riviera Hotel and Casino. Running for an astonishing 22 years (1985-2006), &lt;em&gt;Splash&lt;/em&gt; wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a show; it was a vibrant, evolving reflection of Las Vegas&amp;rsquo; entertainment history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-riviera-and-the-birth-of-an-aquacade&#34;&gt;The Riviera and the Birth of an Aquacade&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Riviera, a legendary landmark on the Strip, was already known for its classic Vegas charm. In June 1985, it upped the ante with &lt;em&gt;Splash&lt;/em&gt;, conceived and produced by Jeff Kutash. Billed as an “aquacade,” the show deliberately distinguished itself from the traditional showgirl revues that dominated the landscape. The centerpiece? A massive 18-foot-tall water tank, integral to the choreography and theatrical experience. This was truly something different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember the Boardwalk? A Look Back at Las Vegas&#39;s Coney Island Dream</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/boardwalk-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/boardwalk-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-holiday-inn-to-coney-island-escape&#34;&gt;From Holiday Inn to Coney Island Escape&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the soaring heights of CityCenter and the elegance of the Waldorf Astoria graced the Las Vegas Strip, a different kind of spectacle stood proudly: the Boardwalk Hotel &amp;amp; Casino. Its story is a microcosm of the Strip’s evolution, from modest beginnings to a playful, themed identity, and ultimately, to its demolition to make way for modern behemoths. The property’s roots stretch back to 1966, initially a fairly unremarkable Holiday Inn. This six-story structure, designed by Homer Rissman, catered to a growing, but still relatively small, Vegas landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember the Golden Goose? A Vintage Las Vegas Story of Grit and Glitter</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/golden-goose-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/golden-goose-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-golden-goose-a-downtown-diamond-in-the-rough&#34;&gt;The Golden Goose: A Downtown Diamond in the Rough&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas, Fremont Street East – it’s a vibrant hub today, but its story is built on decades of evolution. And nestled within that history was the Golden Goose Hotel and Casino, a property that played a significant, if often overlooked, role in the landscape of vintage Las Vegas. Located at 20 Fremont Street, the Golden Goose took flight in 1975, marking a pivotal moment: it was the first casino entirely owned by Herb Pastor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember the Jolly Trolley Casino? A Wild Ride Through Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/jolly-trolley-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/jolly-trolley-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-trolley-full-of-trouble-introducing-jolly-trolley-casino&#34;&gt;A Trolley Full of Trouble: Introducing Jolly Trolley Casino&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen its share of themed casinos, but few were as memorable – or as delightfully scandalous – as the Jolly Trolley Casino. Located at 2440 Las Vegas Boulevard South, right across from the Sahara, the Trolley debuted in 1977, transforming a former shopping center into a vibrant, adult-themed playground. Its eye-catching, trolley-shaped marquee wasn’t just decoration; it perfectly embodied the playful, and at times provocative, atmosphere within. Before the Trolley, the location housed Honest John’s and the Centerfold Casino, each hinting at the adult entertainment that would define Jolly Trolley’s brief but impactful run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering &#39;The Ho&#39;: A Look Back at the Westward Ho Hotel and Casino Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/westward-ho-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/westward-ho-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-frontier-salute-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Frontier Salute on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those who remember the Las Vegas Strip of the 1960s and 70s, the Westward Ho Hotel and Casino – affectionately nicknamed “The Ho” – held a special place. Opened in 1963, nestled between the iconic Stardust and where Slots-A-Fun would later rise, it wasn’t just another casino; it was a respectful nod to the westward expansion that defined Nevada’s history. Brothers and sisters Dean Petersen and his siblings were behind the venture, choosing a name that evoked images of covered wagons and the pioneering spirit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Bourbon Street Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bourbon-street-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bourbon-street-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-shenandoah-to-the-big-easy-a-brief-history&#34;&gt;From Shenandoah to the Big Easy: A Brief History&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before it became the vibrant, if somewhat compact, Bourbon Street Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, the property at 120 E. Flamingo Road in Las Vegas bore a different name: the Shenandoah Hotel. Opened in 1980, the Shenandoah was struggling, and it seemed destined for obscurity. However, a shift in Nevada law in 1985 – allowing foreign ownership of gaming operations – created a pivotal opportunity. Canadian real estate firm Carma Developers (then Allarco Holdings) recognized the potential and swooped in, transforming the struggling Shenandoah into the New Orleans-themed Bourbon Street Hotel &amp;amp; Casino.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Club Bingo: A Vintage Vegas History Lesson</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/club-bingo-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/club-bingo-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-strip-standalone-to-fremont-street-flair-the-story-of-club-bingo-las-vegas&#34;&gt;From Strip Standalone to Fremont Street Flair: The Story of Club Bingo Las Vegas&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before mega-resorts and dazzling spectacles, Las Vegas thrived on simpler pleasures. Among them? Bingo! And for a time, Club Bingo was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to be for locals and tourists alike. Its story offers a fascinating glimpse into the evolution of Las Vegas entertainment, showcasing two distinct eras.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-original-a-post-war-strip-landmark&#34;&gt;The Original: A Post-War Strip Landmark&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Club Bingo first burst onto the scene on July 24, 1947, at 2535 South Las Vegas Boulevard. Imagine the Strip back then - less glitzy, more modest. Milton Prell and Al Winter, seasoned gaming entrepreneurs, envisioned a dedicated 300-seat bingo parlor, complete with the appealing addition of a “Bonanza Room” for dining and entertainment. Managed by Frank Schivo, Club Bingo quickly became a beloved local hangout. It wasn’t a grand palace – the design was intentionally understated – but its electric bingo board sign, a beacon of neon fun, made it instantly recognizable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Coin Castle Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/coin-castle-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/coin-castle-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-royal-welcome-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Royal Welcome on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas&amp;rsquo; Fremont Street has always been a landscape of constant change, but some casinos leave a more enduring mark than others. Coin Castle Casino, a small but spirited property operating from 1970 to 1999, is one such place. For nearly three decades, it offered a unique slice of vintage Las Vegas, a far cry from the mega-resorts that would later dominate the Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Dirty Sally&#39;s: A Disco Legend on the Vintage Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dirty-sallys-discotheque-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dirty-sallys-discotheque-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-boogie-and-backgammon&#34;&gt;A Brief History of Boogie and Backgammon&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been a canvas for bold innovation, and in the mid-1970s, Dirty Sally’s Discotheque added a vibrant splash of color to that ever-changing landscape. Situated at the corner of what was then Twain Avenue (now Sands Avenue), directly on the Strip, the club occupied a space previously known for its own notoriety as Pussycat a’ Go-Go. Prior to its Dirty Sally’s incarnation, it briefly cycled through names like Sully’s and Pigalle, each reflecting the evolving tastes and trends of the era. But it was the “Dirty Sally’s” moniker, around 1974, that truly captured the essence of the place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Dixie Deli: A Vintage Bite of Old Fremont Street, Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dixie-deli-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dixie-deli-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-humble-deli-amidst-the-glitter&#34;&gt;A Humble Deli Amidst the Glitter&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas history isn&amp;rsquo;t just about the glitz and glamour of the Strip’s iconic casinos. It’s also about the everyday places that fueled the city’s growth – the diners, the shops, and the small businesses that served the working class and the visitors who weren&amp;rsquo;t always chasing a jackpot. One such place, though largely forgotten now, was the Dixie Deli (sometimes referred to as Dixie Delicatessen). Situated at 24 Fremont Street, this unassuming deli occupied a small but vital space in the bustling heart of old Fremont Street, roughly from the late 1940s to the early 1960s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering El Rancho Vegas: The First Resort on the Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-rancho-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-rancho-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-birth-of-the-strip-el-rancho-vegas&#34;&gt;The Birth of the Strip: El Rancho Vegas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip as we know it wouldn’t exist without El Rancho Hotel and Casino. Opened on April 3, 1941, it wasn’t just another hotel; it was the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; resort on what was then Highway 91, now the iconic Las Vegas Strip. Visionary businessman Tommy Hull saw the potential of attracting Los Angeles travelers to this desert oasis, and El Rancho was his gamble. Designed by the talented Wayne McAllister, the resort aimed for an Old West charm, a theme that would become a signature of early Las Vegas establishments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering El Rancho: A Second Chance on the Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-rancho-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-rancho-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-ghost-of-vegas-past-the-original-el-rancho-and-its-legacy&#34;&gt;A Ghost of Vegas Past: The Original El Rancho and Its Legacy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For any true vintage Las Vegas enthusiast, the name “El Rancho” conjures images of a bygone era – the pioneering days of the Strip. The original El Rancho Vegas, opened in 1941, was a cornerstone of early tourism, boasting the first cocktail lounge, the first rodeo, and a distinct Western theme that helped define the nascent Las Vegas brand. It was a truly pivotal hotel that paved the way for future development. Sadly, the original El Rancho closed its doors in 1960, leaving a void in the landscape and the collective memory of Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Emerald Green: The Dunes Golf Course and Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dunes-golf-course-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dunes-golf-course-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-strip-oasis-introducing-the-dunes-golf-course&#34;&gt;A Strip Oasis: Introducing the Dunes Golf Course&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before mega-resorts boasted sprawling shopping complexes and themed attractions, Las Vegas’s luxury was defined differently. In the mid-1960s, the Dunes Hotel &amp;amp; Casino made a bold statement: it wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; about gambling. It was about offering a complete resort experience, and a key ingredient in that vision was the Emerald Green golf course. Officially known as the Emerald Green course, it stood as one of only two Strip resorts to feature its own layout – alongside the Desert Inn – and represented a significant departure from the traditional casino-focused model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Fiesta Rancho: A North Las Vegas Local&#39;s Paradise | Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fiesta-rancho-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fiesta-rancho-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-north-las-vegas-institution-the-fiesta-ranchos-story&#34;&gt;A North Las Vegas Institution: The Fiesta Rancho’s Story&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip gets all the glory, but for decades, a different kind of Las Vegas magic happened just a few miles northeast – at the Fiesta Rancho Hotel and Casino. Opened on December 14, 1994, this wasn’t your glitzy, high-roller destination. It was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place for North Las Vegas residents, a true community hub, and a significant milestone for the city&amp;rsquo;s expansion. Developed by the Maloof family, Fiesta (as it was initially known) marked the first hotel-casino to call North Las Vegas home. It started humbly: just 100 rooms and a modest 25,000-square-foot casino.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Fitzgeralds Hotel &amp; Casino: A Downtown Las Vegas Legend</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fitzgeralds-hotel-and-casino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fitzgeralds-hotel-and-casino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-lucky-charm-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Lucky Charm on Fremont Street&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For decades, a towering green and shamrock-laden presence graced the eastern end of Fremont Street: Fitzgeralds Hotel &amp;amp; Casino. More than just a casino, Fitzgeralds represented a distinct era of downtown Las Vegas – one of approachable gaming, quirky theming, and a vibrant, energetic atmosphere. Today, it lives on as The D Las Vegas, but the memories of its former identity remain strong with many long-time Vegas visitors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Fitzgeralds Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Vegas Icon on Fremont Street</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fitgeralds-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fitgeralds-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-sundance-to-shamrock-the-fitzgeralds-story&#34;&gt;From Sundance to Shamrock: The Fitzgeralds Story&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas in the 1980s was a landscape of established casinos and burgeoning growth. Perched at the eastern end of Fremont Street, at 301 Fremont Street, stood what began as the Sundance Hotel. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t just any hotel; it was connected to the legendary Moe Dalitz, a name synonymous with Las Vegas history and the Stardust. Initially managed by Al Sachs and Herb Tobman, the Sundance laid the groundwork for what would become a beloved and uniquely themed casino resort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Fitzgeralds Las Vegas: A Downtown Icon&#39;s Rise and Fall</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fitzgeralds-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fitzgeralds-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-player-on-fremont-street-the-birth-of-fitzgeralds&#34;&gt;A New Player on Fremont Street: The Birth of Fitzgeralds&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas in the 1980s was a vibrant, slightly rough-around-the-edges spectacle. The Strip was evolving, but Fremont Street remained the heart of Vegas excitement. In 1987, a new casino, Fitzgeralds, joined the fray, rising on the site of the previously existing Sundance Hotel and Casino. It was instantly recognizable, boasting a classic, approachable feel, a stark contrast to the increasingly themed and opulent mega-resorts taking shape elsewhere. Fitzgeralds aimed for a comfortable, welcoming atmosphere, appealing to a broad range of players and instantly becoming a downtown staple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Fitzgeralds: A Vintage Las Vegas Gem on Fremont Street</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fitzgeralds-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/fitzgeralds-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-sundance-to-shamrock-the-early-years&#34;&gt;From Sundance to Shamrock: The Early Years&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas has seen its share of transformations, but few are as fondly remembered as Fitzgeralds Hotel &amp;amp; Casino. Located at 301 Fremont Street, anchoring the eastern end of the Fremont Street Experience, it was a visual landmark and a beloved institution for decades. Its story actually begins in 1980 as the Sundance Hotel, a project brought to life by the vision of Moe Dalitz, along with operators Al Sachs and Herb Tobman – the same powerhouse team behind the Stardust and Fremont casinos. While initially a stylish addition to the Fremont Street scene, its identity was about to take a decidedly Irish turn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Foxy’s Firehouse Casino: A Vintage Vegas Gem on the Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/foxys-firehouse-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/foxys-firehouse-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-delis-legacy--a-firehouse-fantasy&#34;&gt;A Deli&amp;rsquo;s Legacy &amp;amp; a Firehouse Fantasy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the megaresorts and sprawling complexes defined the Las Vegas Strip, there were smaller, more intimate gaming venues. Among them, Foxy’s Firehouse Casino stands out as a particularly charming and memorable piece of vintage Vegas history. Located on the northeast corner of Las Vegas Boulevard and Sahara Avenue (now the site of a Walgreens), this little casino operated from 1976 to 1988 and offered a refreshing contrast to the increasingly corporate landscape of the Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Foxy’s: A Vintage Las Vegas Deli Icon | Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/foxys-deli-restaurant-bakery-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/foxys-deli-restaurant-bakery-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;foxys-where-stars-and-sandwiches-met-on-the-las-vegas-strip&#34;&gt;Foxy’s: Where Stars and Sandwiches Met on the Las Vegas Strip&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of us who remember the early days of Las Vegas, the name “Foxy’s Delicatessen, Restaurant, and Bakery” instantly conjures a feeling of warmth, familiarity, and a truly unique slice of Vegas history. Located at the corner of Las Vegas Boulevard and Sahara Avenue (then San Francisco Avenue), Foxy&amp;rsquo;s wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a place to eat; it was a cultural hub, a symbol of the city’s burgeoning spirit, and a testament to the power of a good Reuben sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Glitter Gulch: A Short, Sparkling Chapter in Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/glitter-gulch-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/glitter-gulch-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-flash-of-gold-the-birth-of-glitter-gulch&#34;&gt;A Flash of Gold: The Birth of Glitter Gulch&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen countless casinos rise and fall, each leaving a unique mark on the city&amp;rsquo;s evolving identity. Among those fleeting but memorable landmarks was Glitter Gulch Hotel and Casino, a brief but vibrant player on the scene from 1980 to 1991. Created by the visionary Bob Stupak, the casino aimed to capture the playful, slightly rough-around-the-edges spirit of early Las Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Holy Cow Casino Cafe Brewery: A Vintage Las Vegas Landmark | Vintage Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holy-cow-casino-cafe-brewery-las-vegas-ladies-v-neck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holy-cow-casino-cafe-brewery-las-vegas-ladies-v-neck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-vegas-institution-from-deli-to-brewpub&#34;&gt;A Vegas Institution: From Deli to Brewpub&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas history isn’t just about the glittering Strip we know today. It’s a tapestry woven with quirky, unique businesses that dared to be different. One such gem was the Holy Cow! Casino Cafe Brewery, a distinctive landmark that blended gaming, dining, and brewing innovation at Sahara and the Boulevard. Its story is one of reinvention and pioneering spirit, a far cry from the mega-resorts dominating the landscape now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Holy Cow Casino Cafe Brewery: A Vintage Vegas Brewpub Legend</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holy-cow-casino-cafe-brewery-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holy-cow-casino-cafe-brewery-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-foxys-deli-to-holy-cow-a-tale-of-transformation&#34;&gt;From Foxy’s Deli to Holy Cow!: A Tale of Transformation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before it became the quirky, beer-loving haven we remember, the northeast corner of Sahara and the Strip had a different identity. Originally debuting in 1955 as Foxy’s Deli, it held the distinction of being the Strip’s first integrated restaurant – a groundbreaking concept for the era. Imagine Liberace, Wayne Newton, and Shecky Greene enjoying a casual meal! Foxy’s morphed into Foxy’s Firehouse Casino, continuing operation until 1988. Then, in 1992, Tom “Big Dog” Wiesner purchased the property, revitalizing it with the wonderfully whimsical concept of Holy Cow! Casino Cafe Brewery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Hotel Nevada Las Vegas: A Quiet Corner of Vintage Downtown</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/hotel-nevada-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/hotel-nevada-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-humble-gateway-to-the-neon-city&#34;&gt;A Humble Gateway to the Neon City&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas is synonymous with glitz, glamour, and sprawling mega-resorts. But before the Strip’s transformation and the rise of the themed hotels, a different kind of Las Vegas existed—a working-class hub of modest motels, cafes, and gaming halls. Tucked just south of Fremont Street, at 235 South Main Street, stood the Hotel Nevada, a building that embodies that bygone era. While largely forgotten today, its story is a crucial piece of early Las Vegas history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Key Largo: A Lost Oasis on East Flamingo Road - Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/key-largo-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/key-largo-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-quirky-chapter-the-story-of-key-largo-hotel-and-casino&#34;&gt;A Quirky Chapter: The Story of Key Largo Hotel and Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been about spectacle and reinvention, but just a mile east, on East Flamingo Road, a quieter, slightly offbeat history unfolded at the Key Largo Hotel and Casino. While not a Strip titan, Key Largo held a unique place in the hearts of many Vegas locals and those seeking an alternative to the glitz and glamour downtown. Its story, spanning from 1974 to 2013, is a microcosm of Vegas&amp;rsquo;s evolution and eventual obsolescence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering La Bayou Casino: A Slice of Old Vegas Charm on Fremont Street</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/la-bayou-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/la-bayou-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-coffee-house-to-coin-castle-a-storied-fremont-street-location&#34;&gt;From Coffee House to Coin Castle: A Storied Fremont Street Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;La Bayou Casino, sadly lost to demolition in 2016, occupied a prime spot at 15 East Fremont Street, right on the bustling Fremont Street Experience. But its story goes far deeper than its 17-year run as a casino. The land itself holds a remarkable legacy, starting all the way back in 1913 as the Las Vegas Coffee House. It’s a location intertwined with the very fabric of Las Vegas’s gambling history, becoming the Northern Club in 1920 and famously earning Mayme Stocker the first-ever gaming license in Las Vegas. Through the decades, it’s been known as the Turf Club, Monte Carlo Club, and most memorably, the Coin Castle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering La Bayou Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Treasure &amp; Those Iconic Ladies&#39; V-Necks</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/la-bayou-casino-las-vegas-ladies-v-neck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/la-bayou-casino-las-vegas-ladies-v-neck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-slice-of-new-orleans-charm-on-fremont-street-la-bayous-story&#34;&gt;A Slice of New Orleans Charm on Fremont Street: La Bayou’s Story&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;La Bayou Casino, a fondly remembered landmark on Fremont Street, isn’t just another faded Vegas memory. Its history is deeply intertwined with the evolution of Las Vegas gambling itself. Originally the site of the Las Vegas Coffee House in 1913, the location cycled through various iterations – the Northern Club (holding Vegas’s &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; gaming license thanks to Mayme Stocker!), Turf Club, Monte Carlo Club, and the playful Coin Castle – each adding another layer to its legacy. It wasn’t just a casino; it was a witness to Las Vegas’s burgeoning identity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering La Concha Motel: A Googie Gem Lost &amp; Found on the Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/la-concha-motel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/la-concha-motel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-shell-of-a-story-la-conchas-rise-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Shell of a Story: La Concha’s Rise on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few Las Vegas landmarks sparked as much awe and envy as the La Concha Motel. Opening in 1961 at 2955 Las Vegas Boulevard South, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t just another roadside stop; it was a statement. Owned by M.K. Doumani, the property boasted 350 rooms and, more importantly, a lobby that redefined mid-century modern design. The genius behind this architectural marvel was Paul Revere Williams, a pioneering African American architect whose talent transcended racial barriers in a segregated era. He created a breathtaking concrete-shell lobby, instantly recognizable for its swooping curves and thin-shell design – resembling a giant seashell or a futuristic spaceship, perfectly encapsulating the optimism of the Atomic Age.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Louigi&#39;s: A Vintage Vegas Legend on the Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/louigis-italian-charcoal-broiler-restaurant-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/louigis-italian-charcoal-broiler-restaurant-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-lone-star-on-the-strip-louigis-italian-charcoal-broiler-1951-1965&#34;&gt;A Lone Star on the Strip: Louigi’s Italian Charcoal Broiler (1951-1965)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip of the 1950s was a very different beast than the mega-resort landscape we know today. While lavish hotels were springing up, few stood apart like Louigi’s Italian Charcoal Broiler. Located at 3729 Las Vegas Boulevard South, Louigi’s held the remarkable distinction of being the Strip&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; independent, stand-alone restaurant – a true anomaly amidst the burgeoning resort dining scene. Opened in 1951, it offered a warmth and authenticity hard to find elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Lucky Dragon: A Brief, Bold Chapter in Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lucky-dragon-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lucky-dragon-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-kind-of-vegas-dream-the-lucky-dragons-debut&#34;&gt;A New Kind of Vegas Dream: The Lucky Dragon&amp;rsquo;s Debut&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For decades, Las Vegas has thrived on innovation and reinvention. While mega-resorts and themed experiences are practically synonymous with the Strip, the Lucky Dragon Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, which opened in late 2016, attempted something refreshingly different – an immersive, authentic Asian lifestyle experience. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t just about gambling; it was about a holistic cultural journey. As the first ground-up hotel-casino built since the Cosmopolitan a decade prior, it promised to be a landmark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Mr. Sy&#39;s Casino: A Quirky Slice of Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mr-sys-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mr-sys-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-cartoon-mascot-and-a-mountain-of-bacon-introducing-mr-sys&#34;&gt;A Cartoon Mascot and a Mountain of Bacon: Introducing Mr. Sy’s&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we think of vintage Las Vegas, images of towering hotels and dazzling shows often come to mind. But there was a time when Vegas was defined by smaller, more character-driven establishments, and few were as memorable as Mr. Sy’s Casino. Located just off the Las Vegas Strip, across from the now-iconic Stardust, Mr. Sy’s wasn&amp;rsquo;t about opulence; it was about charm and a distinctly down-to-earth Vegas experience. Opened in 1962, it operated until 1981, a short but impactful run in the city’s evolving landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Nob Hill Casino Las Vegas: A Strip History of Low Limits and Accessible Fun</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/nob-hill-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/nob-hill-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-different-kind-of-strip-experience-introducing-nob-hill-casino&#34;&gt;A Different Kind of Strip Experience: Introducing Nob Hill Casino&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been about spectacle and excess, but tucked between the giants like the Sands and the Holiday Casino, a different kind of experience thrived: Nob Hill Casino. Opening its doors in the summer of 1978, Nob Hill wasn’t aiming for high rollers or themed extravagance. Instead, it catered to budget-minded players and those seeking a more relaxed, accessible nightlife scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Pink E’s Pool Hall: A Vibrant Slice of Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pink-es-pool-hall-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pink-es-pool-hall-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-pink-paradise-on-flamingo-road&#34;&gt;A Pink Paradise on Flamingo Road&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas history isn’t just about the glittering Strip. It&amp;rsquo;s woven into the fabric of neighborhoods and businesses that thrived just beyond the neon lights. One such spot, a vibrant and unforgettable landmark, was Pink E’s Pool Hall (also known as Pink E’s Fun Food &amp;amp; Spirits). Located at 3695 W. Flamingo Road, across from the Rio, Pink E’s was a unique entertainment destination from 1995 until its closure in 2005.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Sassy Sallys Casino: A Vintage Fremont Street Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sassy-sallys-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sassy-sallys-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-dash-of-sass-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Dash of Sass on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of us who remember the vibrant, character-driven days of Downtown Las Vegas, the name “Sassy Sallys” evokes a specific feeling – a playful wink in the neon glow. Located at 32 Fremont Street, in the heart of what&amp;rsquo;s now the Fremont Street Experience, Sassy Sallys Casino wasn’t about extravagant shows or high-roller tables. It was about fun, accessibility, and a healthy dose of Las Vegas personality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Showboat Lanes Las Vegas: A Vintage Bowling Paradise</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/showboat-lanes-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/showboat-lanes-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-bowling-beacon-on-boulder-highway&#34;&gt;A Bowling Beacon on Boulder Highway&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before mega-resorts dominated the landscape, Las Vegas was a city of distinct neighborhoods and unique entertainment offerings. Tucked away on Boulder Highway, the Showboat Hotel and Casino, opening in 1954, aimed to be a locals-friendly alternative to the burgeoning Strip. To achieve that, the Showboat made a bold bet: bowling. Showboat Lanes wasn’t just a bowling alley; it was a destination.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rise-of-a-bowling-empire&#34;&gt;The Rise of a Bowling Empire&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 1950s and 60s saw bowling surge in popularity across the United States, and the Showboat seized the opportunity. They invested heavily, creating a bowling center that shattered records. With over 100 lanes, Showboat Lanes was briefly the largest in the world – a truly impressive feat! This massive scale wasn&amp;rsquo;t just about quantity; it was about creating a complete entertainment experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Silver City Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silver-city-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silver-city-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-short-sparkling-run-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Short, Sparkling Run on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a brief but fascinating period, the Silver City Hotel &amp;amp; Casino occupied a prime location on the Las Vegas Strip. It&amp;rsquo;s a story of ambition, failed dreams, and the relentless churn of Vegas development. The site, originally home to the Riata Casino, felt cursed. The Riata opened in 1973 but closed less than a year later, a victim of poor planning and competition. Enter Major Riddle, a multiple casino owner, who stepped in to resurrect the property in 1974, rebranding it as the Silver City Casino.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Society Cleaners: A Vintage Las Vegas Staple on Fremont Street</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/society-cleaners-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/society-cleaners-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-touch-of-class-on-fremont-the-story-of-society-cleaners&#34;&gt;A Touch of Class on Fremont: The Story of Society Cleaners&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of us who remember old Vegas, the name “Society Cleaners” evokes a particular feeling – reliability, quality, and a quiet understanding of the demands of a city built on appearances. Operating from the 1940s until the 1990s, Society Cleaners wasn’t just a dry cleaner; it was a vital part of the fabric of Las Vegas, quietly supporting the glittering spectacle we associate with the Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Sundance West Casino: A Fremont Street Flashback | Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sundance-west-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sundance-west-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-sparkle-on-fremont-street-sundance-west-casino&#34;&gt;A Brief Sparkle on Fremont Street: Sundance West Casino&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 1970s Fremont Street Experience was a vibrant, chaotic beast – a neon-drenched canyon brimming with casinos vying for attention. Among the giants like the Golden Nugget and Binion’s Horseshoe, Sundance West Casino represented a different kind of ambition, a smaller scale operation aiming for a specific, approachable vibe. Opened in 1976, it stood as a testament to the entrepreneurial spirit that once defined Downtown Las Vegas, a spirit now largely relegated to memory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Terrible’s Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Gem | Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/terribles-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/terribles-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-humble-beginning-from-continental-to-terrible&#34;&gt;A Humble Beginning: From Continental to Terrible&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before it became the affectionately ironic “Terrible’s Hotel and Casino,” the property at 6300 Paradise Road started life as the Continental. It was a solid, if unremarkable, off-Strip establishment catering to locals and budget travelers. For years, the Continental quietly served its purpose, a common sight in the burgeoning landscape just east of the famed Las Vegas Strip. However, its destiny changed in 2000 when Herbst Gaming, the family synonymous with Terrible Herbst gas stations, acquired the property.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the 20th Century Hotel &amp; Casino: A Fleeting Flash of Vegas Glamour | Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/20th-century-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/20th-century-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-spark-of-modernity-the-20th-century-hotel--casino&#34;&gt;A Brief Spark of Modernity: The 20th Century Hotel &amp;amp; Casino&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip is known for constant reinvention, but few properties exemplify this more dramatically than the site currently occupied by the OYO Hotel &amp;amp; Casino on Tropicana Avenue. From 1977 to 1979, it was briefly but memorably the 20th Century Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, a venture born from the ashes of a Howard Johnson’s motel and aimed at capturing the spirit of the mid-century modern aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Alpine Village Inn: A Taste of Bavaria in Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/alpine-village-inn-restaurant-and-inn-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/alpine-village-inn-restaurant-and-inn-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-oasis-of-bavarian-cheer&#34;&gt;A Desert Oasis of Bavarian Cheer&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip’s history is filled with flamboyant themes and larger-than-life experiences, but few establishments cultivated the unique charm of the Alpine Village Inn Restaurant and Inn. From its debut in 1950, this Bavarian-Swiss themed establishment offered a welcome respite from the growing desert city, a taste of Old World hospitality, and a whole lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Founded by Ray Dambach and Pauline Remmert at 905 North Las Vegas Boulevard, the Inn initially catered to a population hungry for something beyond the standard fare. The menu was straightforward – sauerkraut, schnitzel, and hearty potato pancakes – but the ambiance was the real draw. Over the years, the Alpine Village Inn moved several times, each location evolving the experience. The 1953 relocation to Maryland Parkway, followed by a spot across from the Stardust in the Desert Spa Shopping Center, each built upon the Inn’s reputation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Ambassador Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/ambassador-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/ambassador-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-brief-shine-the-ambassador-casinos-vegas-story&#34;&gt;A Brief Shine: The Ambassador Casino&amp;rsquo;s Vegas Story&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been a landscape of constant change, with glittering new resorts rising to eclipse those that came before. But nestled just east of the Strip, at 377 East Flamingo Road, existed a smaller, more intimate gambling experience: the Ambassador Casino. Its story, though brief, provides a fascinating glimpse into a pivotal era of Las Vegas’s evolving gaming scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Bagdad Inn Las Vegas: A Roadside Icon&#39;s History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-bagdad-inn-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-bagdad-inn-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-oasis-for-road-trippers-the-bagdad-inns-beginnings&#34;&gt;A Desert Oasis for Road Trippers: The Bagdad Inn&amp;rsquo;s Beginnings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For decades, the Bagdad Inn stood as a familiar and comforting landmark on Las Vegas Boulevard South. Located near Sahara Avenue, this roadside motel perfectly embodied the spirit of 1950s Las Vegas – a city rapidly expanding to cater to the burgeoning automobile tourism boom. Built during a pivotal era of American travel, the Bagdad Inn was designed specifically for the road tripper, a vital demographic fueling Vegas&amp;rsquo;s growth. It offered a haven of simple comfort and affordability, a far cry from the opulent casinos that were beginning to define the Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Bagdad Inn: A Vintage Las Vegas Roadside Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bagdad-inn-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bagdad-inn-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-oasis-for-road-trippers-the-bagdad-inns-story&#34;&gt;A Desert Oasis for Road Trippers: The Bagdad Inn&amp;rsquo;s Story&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For decades, the Bagdad Inn stood as a familiar and comforting landmark along Las Vegas Boulevard South. Located near Sahara Avenue, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t one of the sprawling casinos – it was a vital piece of the Las Vegas road trip experience, offering affordable lodging and a touch of mid-century hospitality. Built in the 1950s, a period of rapid expansion for Las Vegas, the Bagdad Inn perfectly embodied the burgeoning era of automobile tourism. It catered to the wave of travelers cruising across the country, eager to experience the bright lights and excitement of the burgeoning entertainment capital of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Barbary Coast Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Vegas Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/barbary-coast-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/barbary-coast-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-stylish-alternative-rises-on-the-four-corners&#34;&gt;A Stylish Alternative Rises on the Four Corners&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip in the late 1970s was dominated by sprawling mega-resorts. But nestled at the bustling intersection of Las Vegas Boulevard and Flamingo Road – the legendary “Four Corners” – a different kind of experience was about to emerge. On March 2, 1979, the Barbary Coast Hotel &amp;amp; Casino opened its doors, offering a sophisticated and intimate alternative to the increasingly colossal properties that defined the era.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Barbary Coast Hotel Casino: A Vintage Vegas Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/barbary-coast-hotel-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/barbary-coast-hotel-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-stylish-alternative-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Stylish Alternative on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been about evolution, but sometimes, it’s about offering something &lt;em&gt;different&lt;/em&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s precisely what Michael Gaughan envisioned when he opened the Barbary Coast Hotel &amp;amp; Casino on March 2, 1979. Built on the former site of the Desert Villa/Times Square Motel, the Barbary Coast arrived at a moment when the Strip was increasingly dominated by sprawling mega-resorts. Gaughan, son of downtown casino legend Jackie Gaughan, wanted to create a more intimate and elegant experience – a haven from the overwhelming scale of its neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Big Nickel Rendezvous: A Vintage Vegas Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/big-nickel-rendezvous-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/big-nickel-rendezvous-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-nickels-worth-of-vegas-history&#34;&gt;A Nickel&amp;rsquo;s Worth of Vegas History&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas has always been a whirlwind of reinvention, and few properties exemplify that spirit more than the address at 400 East Ogden Avenue. Today part of the Gold Spike, this spot has worn many faces over the years, but its time as the Rendezvous Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, and later the iconic Big Nickel, represents a specific and intriguing chapter in vintage Las Vegas history. It’s a story of ambition, quick pivots, and the constant struggle for survival in a crowded market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Bingo Palace Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Gem &amp; The Birth of Station Casinos</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bingo-palace-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bingo-palace-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-the-casino-to-the-bingo-palace-humble-beginnings-on-sahara&#34;&gt;From The Casino to the Bingo Palace: Humble Beginnings on Sahara&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling spectacle of modern Las Vegas, there were smaller, more intimate gambling halls catering to a different clientele. One such establishment, quietly but significantly, shaped the future of Las Vegas gaming: The Bingo Palace Casino. Its story began modestly in July 1976 as simply “The Casino,” a 5,000-square-foot operation nestled beside the Mini-Price Motor Inn on Sahara Avenue, just off the famed Las Vegas Strip. This wasn’t a place for high rollers; it was a casual, relaxed spot frequented by casino employees looking to unwind after a long shift. Think 100 slot machines, a few table games, a snack bar, and a welcoming atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Bonanza Hotel &amp; Casino: A Brief &amp; Tumultuous History on the Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bonanza-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bonanza-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-wild-west-welcome-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Wild West Welcome on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts dominated the Las Vegas Strip, there were smaller, quirky properties that helped shape the city&amp;rsquo;s identity. One such gem was the Bonanza Hotel and Casino, a western-themed venture that briefly occupied a now-iconic spot at 3645 South Las Vegas Boulevard, between the Three Coins and the Galaxy Motel. Opened on July 1, 1967, the Bonanza aimed to offer a distinct experience, capitalizing on the enduring appeal of the Wild West.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Bonanza Hotel &amp; Casino: A Short, Storied Chapter on the Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bonanza-hotel-and-casino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bonanza-hotel-and-casino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-brief-blaze-on-the-strip-the-bonanza-hotel--casino&#34;&gt;A Brief Blaze on the Strip: The Bonanza Hotel &amp;amp; Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen its share of comings and goings, of glitz and glamour, and of ambitious ventures that ultimately faded away. Among these fleeting lights was the Bonanza Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, a western-themed property that existed for a mere six years (1967-1973) before succumbing to financial woes and ownership squabbles. Today, its footprint is occupied by the Horseshoe Las Vegas, but the memory of the Bonanza remains a fascinating glimpse into a specific era of Vegas development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Bonanza Hotel &amp; Casino: A Short, Sweet, &amp; Wild Ride on the Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bonanza-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bonanza-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-western-dream-briefly-blooms-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Western Dream Briefly Blooms on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the dazzling mega-resorts, before the choreographed fountains, and even before some of the iconic properties we know today, the Las Vegas Strip was still evolving. A fascinating piece of that evolution was the Bonanza Hotel and Casino, which opened its doors on July 1, 1967, at 3645 South Las Vegas Boulevard. Nestled between the Three Coins and the Galaxy Motel – using them as overflow lodging, showcasing early Strip resourcefulness – the Bonanza attempted to capture the Wild West spirit with a distinct themed design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Bonanza Lodge: A Vintage Fremont Street Motor Court | Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bonanza-lodge-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bonanza-lodge-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-slice-of-early-fremont-street-the-bonanza-lodge&#34;&gt;A Slice of Early Fremont Street: The Bonanza Lodge&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas’s Fremont Street Experience is a whirlwind of light and sound today, but it wasn’t always that way. Before the soaring Viva Vision canopy, before the casinos expanded to encompass entire blocks, Fremont Street was a street slowly evolving into the “Glitter Gulch” we know—and the Bonanza Lodge stood as a quiet observer of that transformation. Located at 1808 Fremont Street, this modest motel offers a tangible glimpse into Las Vegas’s mid-century lodging scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Brewery Restaurant: A Vintage Las Vegas Hangout</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-brewery-restaurant-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-brewery-restaurant-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-slice-of-vegas-life-the-brewery-restaurant&#34;&gt;A Slice of Vegas Life: The Brewery Restaurant&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and celebrity chef empires, Las Vegas had a different kind of charm. Tucked away from the dazzling lights of the Strip, a restaurant called The Brewery Restaurant carved out a special place in the hearts of locals and casino employees alike. Located at 3824 S. Paradise Road, near Paradise and Twain, this beloved establishment represents a distinct era of Las Vegas history – the late 1970s and 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the California Club Casino: A Vintage Vegas Treasure on Fremont Street</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/california-club-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/california-club-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-downtown-gem-the-california-clubs-early-days&#34;&gt;A Downtown Gem: The California Club&amp;rsquo;s Early Days&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts dominated the Las Vegas Strip, downtown Fremont Street was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to be. And tucked into the bustling scene at 101 East Fremont Street sat the California Club Casino, a beloved institution that embodied the spirit of mid-century Las Vegas. Opening in the early 1950s, initially under the ownership of Phil Copley (later Phil Long), the California Club wasn&amp;rsquo;t about dazzling shows or sprawling pools. It was about friendly faces, approachable games, and a welcoming atmosphere that catered to both downtown workers and local residents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the California Club: A Vintage Vegas Downtown Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/california-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/california-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-downtown-staple-the-california-clubs-early-days&#34;&gt;A Downtown Staple: The California Club&amp;rsquo;s Early Days&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of us who truly appreciate vintage Las Vegas, the name “California Club” evokes images of a simpler time on Fremont Street. Located at 101 East Fremont Street, this wasn’t one of the glitzy Strip mega-resorts; it was a cornerstone of the downtown “locals-first” casino scene, a place where friendly service and a welcoming atmosphere reigned supreme. The club first opened its doors in the early 1950s, initially under the ownership of Phil Copley and later Phil Long. Its logo, featuring a friendly bear mascot, became instantly recognizable to locals and visitors alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Carousel Hotel and Casino: A Vintage Vegas Gem Lost to Time</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/carousel-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/carousel-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-whirl-of-fun-the-carousels-rise-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Whirl of Fun: The Carousel&amp;rsquo;s Rise on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and high-roller spectacle, downtown Las Vegas pulsated with a unique, playful energy. A vibrant piece of that history was the Carousel Hotel and Casino, a beloved Fremont Street fixture that operated from 1964 to 1974. Standing prominently on the corner of Fremont and 1st, it was a visual landmark, distinguishable by its bright neon marquee and, of course, its carousel-themed imagery.  It wasn’t about lavish luxury; it was about affordable fun and a genuinely welcoming atmosphere, a stark contrast to the increasingly upscale casinos sprouting along the Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Casbah: A Vintage Las Vegas Strip Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/casbah-hotel-and-casino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/casbah-hotel-and-casino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-taste-of-morocco-on-the-strip-the-casbahs-early-years&#34;&gt;A Taste of Morocco on the Strip: The Casbah’s Early Years&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen countless hotels rise and fall, each leaving its mark on the city’s unique character. One such hotel, the Casbah, stands out for its distinct Moroccan theme and, perhaps more notably, its complicated history. Built in 1963 by the ambitious Danny Jackson, the Casbah aimed to offer a different kind of Vegas experience – a touch of exoticism amidst the burgeoning glitz and neon. Jackson, already a prominent figure in Las Vegas gambling circles, envisioned a casino that transported guests to a North African oasis. The décor was meticulously planned, featuring vibrant colors, intricate tilework, and lush landscaping, all meant to evoke the atmosphere of Morocco.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Casbah: A Vintage Vegas Story of Intrigue &amp; Reinvention</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/casbah-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/casbah-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-oasis-of-intrigue-the-casbahs-early-years&#34;&gt;A Desert Oasis of Intrigue: The Casbah&amp;rsquo;s Early Years&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few Las Vegas landmarks have a history as colorful and complex as the Casbah Hotel and Casino. Opened in 1963 by the ambitious Danny Jackson, the Casbah aimed to transport visitors to a Moroccan fantasy. Located on the Strip (originally at Sahara Avenue, now the site of Las Vegas City Hall), it was designed to evoke the exotic atmosphere of North Africa, with lush landscaping, ornate fountains, and a distinctive architecture. Jackson envisioned a sophisticated, upscale experience, distinct from the other casinos of the time. While initially successful, the Casbah’s reputation quickly began to tarnish.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Desert Inn: A Legend of Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/desert-inn-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/desert-inn-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dawn-of-a-new-era-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;The Dawn of a New Era on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling spectacle of modern Las Vegas, there was a more intimate, elegant charm. The Desert Inn Hotel and Casino, opening its doors on April 24, 1950, embodied that era. As the Strip’s fifth resort, nestled between what would later become iconic landmarks, the Desert Inn was more than just a hotel and casino; it was a pivotal moment in Las Vegas history. It signaled a shift from small-town gambling halls to a vision of sophisticated entertainment and luxury.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Dunes: A Vintage Las Vegas Strip Icon</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dunes-hotel-and-casino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dunes-hotel-and-casino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-oasis-built-on-ambition-and-uncertainty&#34;&gt;A Desert Oasis Built on Ambition and Uncertainty&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few Las Vegas resorts have a history as turbulent and fascinating as The Dunes. Opening its doors on May 23, 1955, as the tenth resort on the burgeoning Las Vegas Strip, The Dunes aimed to be a high-roller haven. Its early days, however, were far from glamorous. Initial ownership proved shaky, plagued by poor management and a downturn in tourism. The Sands Corporation stepped in to manage the property, but their efforts yielded little improvement, and they quickly retreated. It seemed The Dunes was destined to be a footnote in Las Vegas history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Dunes: A Vintage Las Vegas Strip Legend</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dunes-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dunes-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-desert-dream-the-rise-and-fall-of-the-dunes-hotel-and-casino&#34;&gt;A Desert Dream: The Rise and Fall of the Dunes Hotel and Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen its share of grand dames and glittering newcomers, but few hold a place in history quite like the Dunes Hotel and Casino. Opening its doors on May 23, 1955, as the tenth resort on the Strip, The Dunes represented a bold ambition in a rapidly evolving landscape. Initially, it felt more like a gamble than a sure thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Dunes: A Vintage Las Vegas Strip Legend</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dunes-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/dunes-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-oasis-emerges-the-dunes-opens-its-doors&#34;&gt;A Desert Oasis Emerges: The Dunes Opens Its Doors&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few Las Vegas institutions evoke quite the same sense of faded glamour and intrigue as the Dunes Hotel and Casino. Opening its doors on May 23, 1955, it was the tenth resort to grace the Las Vegas Strip, a pivotal point in the burgeoning city’s development. Initially a gamble by a group of investors, the Dunes quickly found itself struggling. Early management was… problematic, and the fledgling resort floundered under declining tourism, prompting a brief, unsuccessful stint under the Sands&amp;rsquo; management.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Flame Steakhouse: A Vintage Vegas Dining Experience</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/flame-steakhouse-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/flame-steakhouse-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-beacon-of-sophistication-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Beacon of Sophistication on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been about spectacle, but in the early 1960s, it also held a certain understated elegance. Amidst the rising neon and showstopping casinos, The Flame Steakhouse emerged as a treasured oasis of refined dining. Opening in 1961 across from the Silver Slipper Hotel and Casino, The Flame wasn’t about flashing lights or elaborate shows; it was about exceptional food, impeccable service, and a sophisticated atmosphere – a rare find in a city rapidly transforming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Flamingo Capri: A Quiet Bridge in Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/flamingo-capri-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/flamingo-capri-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-unique-spot-on-the-strip-the-flamingo-capri-emerges&#34;&gt;A Unique Spot on the Strip: The Flamingo Capri Emerges&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you think of classic Las Vegas, towering resorts and dazzling spectacle immediately come to mind. But the evolution of the Strip wasn&amp;rsquo;t always about mega-hotels. Tucked between the pioneering Flamingo Hotel and what’s now The LINQ, the Flamingo Capri Hotel and Casino quietly played a crucial role in that transition. Opened on October 30, 1959, by George E. Goldberg and Bill Capri (whose last name gave the motel its distinctive suffix), the Capri was a luxury motel aiming to offer something different. For roughly $2 million, they built a 180-room haven that skillfully bridged the gap between the older motor court era and the burgeoning resort era.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Friendly Club Casino: A Vintage Fremont Street Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/friendly-club-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/friendly-club-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-friendly-face-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Friendly Face on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas in the late 1970s and early 80s was a vibrant, almost chaotic landscape. Fremont Street, then known as “Glitter Gulch,” was a neon-drenched hub of gaming and entertainment, a far cry from the immersive Fremont Street Experience we know today. Amidst the flashing lights and growing grandeur, smaller, neighborhood casinos thrived. One of these, the Friendly Club Casino, stands out in memory, not for its size or extravagance, but for its genuine charm and approachable vibe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Frontier Hotel &amp; Casino: A Wild West Chapter in Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/frontier-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/frontier-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-rollercoaster-of-names-and-ownership-the-frontiers-tumultuous-past&#34;&gt;A Rollercoaster of Names and Ownership: The Frontier&amp;rsquo;s Tumultuous Past&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the glittering megaresorts, before the themed hotels, the northern end of the Las Vegas Strip was home to a place that epitomized the raw, frontier spirit of the burgeoning desert city: The Frontier Hotel and Casino. But its story is far more complex than just a single name. The location itself has worn many hats, starting as Pair O’ Dice in 1931 and cycling through Hotel Last Frontier and New Frontier before finally settling on its most recognizable moniker in 1967.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Gamblers Hall of Fame Casino: A Fleeting Vegas Legend | Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/gamblers-hall-of-fame-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/gamblers-hall-of-fame-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-brief-sparkle-the-gamblers-hall-of-fame-casino&#34;&gt;A Brief Sparkle: The Gamblers Hall of Fame Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas has seen its share of casinos rise and fall, each leaving a unique mark on the city’s vibrant history. Among them, the Gamblers Hall of Fame Casino, which briefly occupied 32 Fremont Street, stands as a particularly intriguing, if short-lived, example of the era’s ambitions and complexities. Opened in 1974, it took over the spot previously held by the Carousel Casino, and represented a bold concept – a casino celebrating poker legends and gaming luminaries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Gamblers Hall of Fame: A Fleeting Legend of Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/gamblers-hall-of-fame-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/gamblers-hall-of-fame-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-different-kind-of-fame-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Different Kind of Fame on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas, especially Fremont Street, has always been a breeding ground for unique and often short-lived themed casinos. But few were as ambitious, or as quickly forgotten, as the Gamblers Hall of Fame. Opened in 1974 at 32 Fremont Street, taking over the Carousel Casino’s former space, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a place to wager; it was intended to be a shrine to the legends of poker and gaming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Gold Key Motel: A Slice of Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/gold-key-motel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/gold-key-motel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-humble-gem-on-a-growing-strip&#34;&gt;A Humble Gem on a Growing Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas in the 1950s and 60s wasn&amp;rsquo;t all shimmering towers and extravagant shows. It was a city still in rapid transformation, and vital to that growth were the motels that lined the budding Las Vegas Strip. Among these, the Gold Key Motel held a modest but memorable place. Opening in 1960, it wasn’t aiming for the luxury clientele of the Desert Inn or the Stardust, but it provided a crucial service – affordable, comfortable lodging for the flood of tourists arriving by car and eager to explore what Vegas had to offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Golden Slot Club: A Downtown Vegas Landmark | Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/golden-slot-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/golden-slot-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-sparkling-start-on-fremont-street-the-golden-slot-club-1955-1958&#34;&gt;A Sparkling Start on Fremont Street: The Golden Slot Club (1955-1958)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas, or “Glitter Gulch” as it was affectionately known, was a kaleidoscope of themed casinos and dazzling signs in the 1950s. Amongst them shone the Golden Slot Club, a small but memorable casino that occupied 22 E. Fremont Street from 1955 to 1958. It’s a name that often gets overlooked in discussions of the Strip’s major players, but the Golden Slot Club represents a key element of vintage Las Vegas – its playful, imaginative architecture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Hacienda Hotel and Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Icon</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/hacienda-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/hacienda-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-mexican-fiesta-on-the-strip-the-haciendas-debut&#34;&gt;A Mexican Fiesta on the Strip: The Hacienda&amp;rsquo;s Debut&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wasn&amp;rsquo;t always the glitzy spectacle we know today. Before mega-resorts and themed hotels, there was the Hacienda Hotel and Casino. Officially opening its doors on October 17, 1956, this $6 million property, the brainchild of Warren Bayley, offered something different to the burgeoning Las Vegas landscape. While Bayley had successful “Hacienda” ventures in California, getting the Nevada Gaming Commission’s approval wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy, leading to initial delays. But once open, it was immediately distinct.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Holiday International Casino: A Brief, Bright Spark in Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holiday-international-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holiday-international-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-bold-bet-the-holiday-internationals-arrival-in-1978&#34;&gt;A Bold Bet: The Holiday International&amp;rsquo;s Arrival in 1978&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas in the late 1970s was a different beast than the mega-resort landscape we know today. The area was still the heart of the city&amp;rsquo;s gaming scene, but competition was fierce. Enter the Holiday International Casino, opening its doors on June 30, 1978, as a joint venture between Holiday Inn and local investors. It was an ambitious project aiming to combine midscale hotel accommodations with a full-fledged casino, appealing to both tourists and the local gambling crowd. The bold concept, the Holiday Inn brand recognition, and the lease agreement with the experienced (and sometimes controversial) Major Riddle, seemed like a winning combination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Holiday Motel Las Vegas: A Neon Icon of the Strip&#39;s Golden Age</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holiday-motel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holiday-motel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-slice-of-mid-century-motor-court-magic&#34;&gt;A Slice of Mid-Century Motor Court Magic&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wasn&amp;rsquo;t always a landscape of towering mega-resorts. In the post-war boom of the early 1950s, it was a burgeoning ribbon of roadside motels catering to the growing wave of auto travelers. Among them shone the Holiday Motel, a beloved fixture along U.S. 91 (now Las Vegas Boulevard) that perfectly embodies the era&amp;rsquo;s optimistic spirit. Originally debuting as the Holiday Inn (completely unrelated to the later national hotel chain) in 1952, it rebranded as the Holiday Motel by the early 1960s, mirroring the changing landscape of travel and roadside hospitality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Hotel San Remo: A Taste of Italy on the Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/hotel-san-remo-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/hotel-san-remo-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-different-kind-of-strip-experience&#34;&gt;A Different Kind of Strip Experience&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The late 1980s and early 1990s in Las Vegas were a time of explosive growth. Megaresorts like the Mirage and Luxor were changing the face of the Strip, promising spectacle and excess. But nestled just east of this rising tide of behemoths, a different kind of oasis opened its doors: the Hotel San Remo. On July 1, 1989, Japanese businessman Sukeaki Izumi unveiled his vision – a mid-sized resort that prioritized intimacy, affordability, and a distinctly European flair. Replacing a Polynesian-themed resort on Tropicana Avenue, the San Remo offered something unique.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Imperial Palace: A Vintage Las Vegas Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/imperial-palace-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/imperial-palace-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-flamingo-capri-to-imperial-grandeur&#34;&gt;From Flamingo Capri to Imperial Grandeur&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen countless transformations, but few were as distinct as the rise and fall of the Imperial Palace Hotel and Casino. Originally the Flamingo Capri, a humble motel, the property at 3535 Las Vegas Boulevard underwent a dramatic rebirth in the early 1970s thanks to entrepreneur Ralph Engelstad. While he initially added a small casino in 1972, the real magic happened on November 1, 1979, when the Imperial Palace officially debuted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Jackpot Casino &amp; Restaurant: A Slice of Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/jackpot-casino-and-restaurant-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/jackpot-casino-and-restaurant-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-simple-proposition-on-a-changing-strip&#34;&gt;A Simple Proposition on a Changing Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip in the early 1970s was a different beast than the mega-resort playground we know today. While the glitter was certainly present, it was often interwoven with a more accessible, down-to-earth vibe. Tucked into the northeast corner of Sahara Avenue and Las Vegas Boulevard, at 2410 South Las Vegas Boulevard, sat a small but memorable player: the Jackpot Casino &amp;amp; Restaurant. Operating from 1971 until roughly 1977-1978, this establishment epitomized a specific moment in Vegas history – a time before the relentless expansion and the escalating price tags that would define the later decades.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Jamaica Motel: A Slice of Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/jamaica-motel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/jamaica-motel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-roadside-oasis-the-jamaica-motels-early-days&#34;&gt;A Roadside Oasis: The Jamaica Motel&amp;rsquo;s Early Days&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip in the 1960s wasn&amp;rsquo;t the sprawling, mega-resort landscape we know today. Instead, it was a vibrant tapestry of smaller, independent motels, each vying for the attention of travelers hitting the road. Among these was the Jamaica Motel, a modest but dependable roadside motor court located at 3745 South Las Vegas Boulevard, just south of Tropicana Avenue. Opened in the early &amp;rsquo;60s, it was a product of its time - a place offering clean, affordable lodging for those seeking a convenient Strip base.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the King 8 Hotel: A Vintage Las Vegas Gem Lost to Time</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/king-8-hotel-gambling-hall-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/king-8-hotel-gambling-hall-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-mid-strip-memory-the-king-8-hotel-gambling-hall&#34;&gt;A Mid-Strip Memory: The King 8 Hotel Gambling Hall&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip is a constantly evolving landscape. Landmarks rise and fall, themes change, and entire properties vanish to make way for the next big thing. While the mega-resorts dominate headlines, it’s important to remember the “in-between” properties – the ones that quietly served a vital purpose and offered a slightly different Las Vegas experience. The King 8 Hotel &amp;amp; Gambling Hall, located at 3330 West Tropicana Avenue, was one such place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Klondike Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Vegas Landmark</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/klondike-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/klondike-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-humble-start-from-kona-kai-to-klondike&#34;&gt;A Humble Start: From Kona Kai to Klondike&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling fountains, the Las Vegas Strip was a different beast. Situated prominently between the iconic “Welcome to Fabulous Las Vegas” sign and the then-newly-built McCarran International Airport, the Klondike Hotel and Casino held a unique spot in that history. It began its life in 1962 as the Kona Kai Motel, a modest roadside stop catering to travelers passing through. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a glamorous beginning, but it was the foundation for what would become a beloved local institution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Las Vegas Club: A Downtown Icon&#39;s Legacy | Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/las-vegas-club-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/las-vegas-club-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-downtown-legend-the-las-vegas-club&#34;&gt;A Downtown Legend: The Las Vegas Club&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Club. Just the name evokes a specific era of Downtown Las Vegas – a time of gritty charm, burgeoning entertainment, and the dawn of themed casino experiences. For 85 years, it stood as an anchor on Fremont Street, a testament to the city&amp;rsquo;s evolving identity. Its closure in 2015 marked the end of an era, but its legacy lives on in the memories of countless visitors and locals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Lotus Inn and Casino: A Vintage Slice of Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lotus-inn-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lotus-inn-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-lotus-blooms-on-the-strip-the-1960s-and-early-70s&#34;&gt;A Lotus Blooms on the Strip: The 1960s and Early 70s&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wasn&amp;rsquo;t always a landscape of sprawling mega-resorts. In the 1960s and early 1970s, a vibrant boom in motel-and-casino development created a distinct character – a patchwork of independent properties catering to a wider range of budgets. Nestled at 1213 South Las Vegas Boulevard, the Lotus Inn and Casino was a quintessential example of this era. Emerging around 1964, it offered a unique combination of low-rise motel accommodations, casino gaming, and classic roadside appeal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Lucky Strike Club Casino: A Downtown Las Vegas Gem | Vintage Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lucky-strike-club-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lucky-strike-club-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-lucky-name-a-lucky-location-the-rise-of-the-lucky-strike-club&#34;&gt;A Lucky Name, A Lucky Location: The Rise of the Lucky Strike Club&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The early days of Las Vegas were defined by a gritty charm and a palpable sense of possibility. Downtown, specifically Fremont Street, was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to be. Amidst the neon glow of the Golden Nugget, the Las Vegas Club, and others, the Lucky Strike Club Casino (located at 117 Fremont Street) carved out its own memorable niche. Opening its doors in 1954, the Lucky Strike wasn&amp;rsquo;t about opulent grandeur – it was about accessibility, friendliness, and that unmistakable Las Vegas vibe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Lucky Strike Club: A Vintage Vegas Gem on Fremont Street</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lucky-strike-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lucky-strike-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-lucky-name-a-lucky-location&#34;&gt;A Lucky Name, a Lucky Location&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 1950s. Downtown Las Vegas, or “Glitter Gulch” as it was affectionately known, was the undisputed entertainment capital of the world. Neon signs blazed, the clatter of slot machines filled the air, and the promise of a big win hung heavy in the desert breeze. Among the iconic establishments that defined this golden age was the Lucky Strike Club, a beloved fixture at 117 Fremont Street. Opened in 1954, the club’s name was a clever nod to both Las Vegas’s obsession with chance and the wildly popular Lucky Strike cigarettes – a reflection of postwar American pop culture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Marina Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Strip Landmark</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/marina-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/marina-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-slice-of-mid-70s-vegas-the-rise-of-the-marina-hotel&#34;&gt;A Slice of Mid-70s Vegas: The Rise of the Marina Hotel&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen countless transformations, but few stories are as poignant as that of the Marina Hotel and Casino. Built in 1975, the Marina wasn’t just another hotel; it represented a moment in Vegas history, a shift toward larger-scale resorts while still retaining a certain retro charm. Conceived by Tom Wiesner, and developed by his Wiesner Investment Company, the Marina sprung from the ashes of the older Golf Club Motel (which later briefly became the Mariner). Its opening on May 1st, 1975, marked a significant expansion of the Strip’s offerings, boasting 714 rooms spread across 14 floors, along with a bustling casino, two restaurants, and a lively entertainment lounge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Maxim Hotel and Casino: A Vintage Vegas Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/maxim-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/maxim-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-smaller-strip-a-bigger-touch&#34;&gt;A Smaller Strip, a Bigger Touch&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip of the 1970s and 80s was a different beast than the mega-resort landscape we know today. Amongst the giants, the Maxim Hotel and Casino, opening its doors on July 1, 1977, carved out a distinctive niche. Located at 160 E Flamingo Rd, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the largest property on the Strip, but it possessed a charm and personalized service that many of its competitors lacked.  Think of it as an antidote to the growing impersonal scale of Vegas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Mint Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Icon | Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-mint-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-mint-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-neon-beacon-on-fremont-street-the-rise-of-the-mint&#34;&gt;A Neon Beacon on Fremont Street: The Rise of The Mint&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mid-1950s were a period of explosive growth for Las Vegas, and no building symbolized that boom quite like The Mint Hotel and Casino. Officially opening its doors on July 12, 1957, The Mint wasn’t just a casino; it was a statement. Conceived by a powerhouse group of partners – Milton Prell, Al Winter, L.B. “Tutor” Scherer, and J.D. “Joe” Hall – with the astute Sam Boyd at the helm as general manager, The Mint aimed to be something special. And it succeeded, spectacularly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Monte Carlo: A Vintage Las Vegas Icon</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/monte-carlo-resort-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/monte-carlo-resort-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-touch-of-monaco-on-the-las-vegas-strip&#34;&gt;A Touch of Monaco on the Las Vegas Strip&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a generation of Las Vegas visitors, the name “Monte Carlo” conjures a specific feeling: a touch of European elegance offered at a surprisingly approachable price. Opened on June 21, 1996, the resort, a joint venture between Mirage Resorts and Circus Circus Enterprises, was a deliberate attempt to inject classic glamour onto the Las Vegas Strip. It stood where the Desert Rose Motel and a portion of the Dunes golf course once resided, a powerful statement about the Strip&amp;rsquo;s evolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the New Frontier: A Vintage Las Vegas Legend</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-frontier-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-frontier-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-frontier-to-new-frontier-a-wild-west-start&#34;&gt;From Frontier to New Frontier: A Wild West Start&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling lights, the Las Vegas Strip was a rough-and-tumble place. In 1942, Harry Brandeis and Guy McAfee envisioned a Western-themed hotel and casino at the far end of the Strip, then a dusty stretch far from the city’s center. Thus, the Frontier Hotel and Casino was born, embracing a Wild West aesthetic with cowboys, horses, and a distinctly untamed atmosphere. The Frontier quickly became a popular spot, particularly appealing to those seeking a more authentic, less polished Vegas experience. It offered affordable rooms and gambling, catering to a middle-class clientele—a crucial segment that helped fuel the city’s growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Oasis Cafe: A Vintage Gem on Fremont Street | Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/oasis-cafe-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/oasis-cafe-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-bloom-the-oasis-cafes-early-days&#34;&gt;A Desert Bloom: The Oasis Cafe&amp;rsquo;s Early Days&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling shows, before the High Roller and the LINQ, Fremont Street was a bustling heart of a much smaller Las Vegas. And at the center of it, for a significant chunk of that early history, sat the Oasis Café. Founded in the 1920s – originally simply called “Oasis” – this unassuming spot at 123 Fremont Street played a vital role in shaping the city’s identity. Think of it as a quiet corner of respite amidst the burgeoning gambling and entertainment district.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Oasis Casino: A Blast from Vintage Las Vegas&#39;s Past</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/oasis-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/oasis-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-modern-refresh-for-a-vegas-legend-the-dunes--the-oasis-casino&#34;&gt;A Modern Refresh for a Vegas Legend: The Dunes &amp;amp; the Oasis Casino&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The early 1980s were a time of rapid change and intense competition on the Las Vegas Strip. The Dunes Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, a beloved and iconic Arabian-themed resort, was showing its age. Seeking a revitalization and a much-needed boost in capacity, the property embarked on a bold project: the Oasis Casino.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Opened in August 1982 at the bustling intersection of Las Vegas Boulevard and Flamingo Road, the Oasis was a striking architectural departure from the Dunes’ original Moorish design. Its sleek, black mirrored-glass facade screamed modern – a clear statement of intent to attract a new generation of casino-goers. This wasn’t subtle renovation; it was a bold expansion, adding approximately 18,000 square feet of gaming space to the resort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Opera House Hotel &amp; Casino: A Slice of Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/opera-house-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/opera-house-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-theatrical-beginning-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Theatrical Beginning on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before mega-resorts and dazzling shows, the Las Vegas Strip was a collection of smaller, character-filled establishments. Among them stood the Opera House Hotel and Casino, a landmark that, while relatively short-lived, left a mark on the city’s evolution. Originally built in 1956 as the Thunderbird Hotel, the property underwent a rebranding in 1963, taking on the name “Opera House.” This name change was meant to reflect its connection to a performance venue that once stood nearby, aiming to evoke a sense of classic Vegas entertainment. The original Thunderbird, with its distinctive architecture, was already a fixture on the Strip, and the Opera House attempted to build on that existing recognition while projecting a slightly more upscale image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Original Sahara Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Icon</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sahara-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sahara-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-dream-takes-shape-the-saharas-debut&#34;&gt;A Desert Dream Takes Shape: The Sahara’s Debut&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling spectacles we associate with the Las Vegas Strip today, there was the Sahara Hotel and Casino. Opening its doors on October 7, 1952, it represented a pivotal moment in Las Vegas’s burgeoning casino era. As the sixth resort to grace the Strip, the Sahara, sprawling across 20 acres, quickly carved out its own distinct identity – a vibrant, themed oasis far removed from the dusty desert landscape. With 240 rooms, each boasting a patio or balcony, and a workforce of 500, it was a significant undertaking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Paddlewheel Hotel and Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Tale</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/paddlewheel-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/paddlewheel-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-royal-inn-to-riverboat-dream-the-paddlewheels-genesis&#34;&gt;From Royal Inn to Riverboat Dream: The Paddlewheel&amp;rsquo;s Genesis&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few Las Vegas properties evoke quite the nostalgic pangs as the Paddlewheel Hotel and Casino. Located at 305 Convention Center Drive (now destined for the Majestic Las Vegas high-rise), its story began in 1970 as the Royal Inn and Casino. For years, it existed as a relatively unassuming fixture on Convention Center Drive, quietly serving a clientele largely connected to the nearby convention center. However, the 1980s brought a dramatic makeover and a radical change of identity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Park Hotel and Casino: A Downtown Las Vegas Lost Treasure</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-park-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-park-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-park-hotel-and-casino-a-brief-turbulent-life-downtown&#34;&gt;The Park Hotel and Casino: A Brief, Turbulent Life Downtown&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas boasts a vibrant, albeit sometimes tumultuous, history. Amongst the neon glow and echoes of the past lies the former site of The Park Hotel and Casino, a building that, despite its short lifespan, tells a compelling story of labor disputes, ownership changes, and the evolving landscape of the Vegas Strip. Located at 200 North Main Street, very close to the heart of Fremont Street, The Park (previously the Holiday International) is now occupied by the popular Main Street Station casino, but its legacy remains for those who remember.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Pioneer Club Hotel and Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Icon</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pioneer-club-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pioneer-club-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-restaurant-to-vegas-landmark-the-pioneers-early-years&#34;&gt;From Restaurant to Vegas Landmark: The Pioneer&amp;rsquo;s Early Years&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The corner of First and Fremont Street in Las Vegas holds a lot of history, and the building currently housing a souvenir shop is no exception. Long before the mega-resorts and dazzling lights, a simple restaurant stood there, dating back to 1918. But it was in 1942 that it truly began its journey toward becoming a legendary Las Vegas institution – the Pioneer Club. Initially a club and cocktail lounge, it quickly became a popular spot for locals and visitors seeking a taste of the burgeoning Vegas nightlife.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Pyramids Motel: A Tiny Landmark in Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pyramids-motel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pyramids-motel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-glimpse-of-early-strip-dreams-the-pyramids-motel&#34;&gt;A Glimpse of Early Strip Dreams: The Pyramids Motel&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip we know today – a dazzling expanse of mega-resorts and themed attractions – didn&amp;rsquo;t spring up overnight. It evolved, brick by brick, motel by motel. Tucked amidst the giants like the Flamingo and the Sands, a small but charming property called the Pyramids Motel played a vital role in that early evolution. Opened in December 1952, the same day as the Sands, it’s a reminder of a different era on the Strip, one of ambitious small-scale developers and the burgeoning entertainment scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Red Barn: A Vintage Las Vegas LGBTQ&#43; Landmark</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/red-barn-bar-and-nightclub-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/red-barn-bar-and-nightclub-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-antiques-to-acceptance-the-early-years&#34;&gt;From Antiques to Acceptance: The Early Years&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few places in Las Vegas history had as multifaceted a beginning as The Red Barn. Located at 1317 Bond Road, a bit off the then-emerging Strip near Tropicana and Maryland Parkway, it started in 1958 not as a raucous nightclub, but as an antique store. Imagine travelers, venturing beyond the main casino drag, stopping by to peruse vintage treasures – a unique offering in a town still defining its identity. The early 1960s saw a significant shift. New ownership reimagined the space, transforming it into a cocktail lounge and bar. While initially a general entertainment spot, it slowly began to cultivate a specific, and vital, identity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Red Garter Casino: A Fleeting Flash of Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/red-garter-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/red-garter-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-brief-sparkle-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Brief Sparkle on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts reigned supreme on the Las Vegas Strip, downtown held its own unique charm. Tucked into the heart of Fremont Street, a vibrant hub then known as “Glitter Gulch,” sat the Red Garter Casino. Opened on May 23, 1972, this compact casino offered a glimpse into a different era – one dominated by smaller, independent operators carving out their space in a booming, but evolving, market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Regent: A Glimpse into Vintage Las Vegas Luxury in Summerlin</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-regent-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-regent-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-bold-vision-the-regent-hotel-and-casino-emerges&#34;&gt;A Bold Vision: The Regent Hotel and Casino Emerges&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas history is filled with ambitious projects, some soaring to iconic status, others fading into memory. The Regent Hotel and Casino, which opened its doors in 1999, falls into the latter category, but its brief existence offers a fascinating glimpse into the late 1990s Las Vegas landscape. Developed by Swiss Casinos, the Regent was conceived as a high-end, European-inspired resort in the burgeoning northwest valley of Summerlin. This was a deliberate departure from the increasingly themed and massive megaresorts dominating the Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Riv: A Look Back at the Riviera Hotel and Casino Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/riviera-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/riviera-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-skyscraper-arrives-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Skyscraper Arrives on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Riviera Hotel and Casino, affectionately known as “The Riv,” was a crucial piece of Las Vegas history. Opening its doors on April 20, 1955, it wasn’t just another casino; it was the first skyscraper in the Las Vegas Valley. Nine stories and 291 rooms seemed futuristic for the burgeoning Strip at the time, instantly changing the skyline and setting a new standard for Vegas resorts. The Riviera was a French-themed oasis, bringing a touch of European elegance to the desert. It represented the ambition and rapid growth characterizing the Las Vegas era of the 1950s – a time when the city was actively courting tourists and solidifying its place as the entertainment capital of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Road Runner Saloon: A Vintage Vegas Locals&#39; Hangout | Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/road-runner-saloon-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/road-runner-saloon-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-different-kind-of-vegas-east-las-vegas-and-the-road-runner-saloon&#34;&gt;A Different Kind of Vegas: East Las Vegas and the Road Runner Saloon&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the Las Vegas Strip roared with neon and spectacle, a different kind of Vegas thrived just a few miles east. This was East Las Vegas, a community of hardworking families and a growing population that craved a more accessible and comfortable nightlife. And for many years, the Road Runner Saloon at 4425 E. Stewart Avenue was the perfect embodiment of that local scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Royal Casino Las Vegas: A Quiet Strip Neighbor&#39;s History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-convention-center-stalwart-the-royals-early-days&#34;&gt;A Convention Center Stalwart: The Royal&amp;rsquo;s Early Days&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just a stone&amp;rsquo;s throw east of the legendary Las Vegas Strip, at 99 Convention Center Drive, stood a hotel with a story uniquely intertwined with the city’s booming convention business. Originally opening in 1970 as Royal Las Vegas, it was part of the Royal Executive Inns chain, a budget-friendly option catering to the growing influx of business travelers. Unlike its glitzy Strip counterparts, the Royal aimed to provide reliable, affordable lodging – a vital service as the Las Vegas Convention Center became an increasingly important economic driver.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Royal Hotel and Casino: A Quiet Legacy on Las Vegas&#39;s Convention Drive</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-convention-focused-beginning-1970-1973&#34;&gt;A Convention-Focused Beginning (1970-1973)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just east of the dazzling Las Vegas Strip, nestled near the bustling Las Vegas Convention Center, stood the Royal Hotel and Casino. Its story begins in 1970 as the “Royal Las Vegas,” part of the Royal Executive Inns chain. Unlike its glamorous neighbors, the Royal wasn&amp;rsquo;t vying for the high-roller crowd. Instead, it strategically targeted the burgeoning convention and business travel market, a crucial and often overlooked engine of Vegas’s early growth. The original concept prioritized practicality and affordability, offering a clean, convenient lodging option for those attending trade shows and conferences – a far cry from the opulent themed resorts starting to dominate the Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Royal Inn Hotel and Casino: A Forgotten Slice of Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-inn-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-inn-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-humble-beginning-the-royal-inn-joins-the-strip-landscape&#34;&gt;A Humble Beginning: The Royal Inn Joins the Strip Landscape&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and sprawling complexes dominated the Las Vegas Strip, smaller, more intimate hotels dotted the landscape. One such property was the Royal Inn Hotel and Casino, a 12-story, 200-room establishment that opened its doors on April 19, 1970, just east of the main action. Costing $3 million to build, it was part of the Royal Inns of America chain, a popular motel brand at the time. Though relatively small by Vegas standards even then, the Royal Inn offered a comfortable and affordable option for visitors, signaling a period of expansion beyond the iconic downtown casinos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Royal Palms Motel: A Vintage Slice of Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-palms-motel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-palms-motel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-roadside-oasis-before-the-mega-resorts&#34;&gt;A Roadside Oasis Before the Mega-Resorts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wasn’t always a landscape of colossal hotels and dazzling fountains. In the 1950s, it was defined by motor courts and roadside motels catering to the wave of motorists flocking to Nevada. Among these quintessential establishments was the Royal Palms Motel, a vital piece of vintage Las Vegas history. Built in 1953-54 by Nate and Jerome Mack on what is now South Las Vegas Boulevard (then South Fifth Street), the Royal Palms represented a pivotal moment – the transition from a sleepy desert outpost to a bustling entertainment destination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Royal Resort: A Quiet Chapter in Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-resort-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-resort-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-convention-focused-beginning-royal-las-vegas-1970-1973&#34;&gt;A Convention-Focused Beginning: Royal Las Vegas (1970-1973)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;East of the dazzling lights of the Las Vegas Strip, a different kind of hospitality began in 1970. The Royal Las Vegas, originally part of the Royal Executive Inns chain, emerged at 99 Convention Center Drive. This wasn’t intended to be a Strip spectacle. The focus was squarely on servicing the burgeoning convention and business travel market that was increasingly important to Las Vegas’s economy. Located right next to the Las Vegas Convention Center, it offered a convenient and, importantly, more affordable alternative to the glitzier resorts further west.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Sal Sagev Hotel: A Vintage Las Vegas Treasure</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sal-sagev-hotel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sal-sagev-hotel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-clever-name-a-storied-past-the-sal-sagev-hotel&#34;&gt;A Clever Name, a Storied Past: The Sal Sagev Hotel&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas is brimming with history, but few properties hold as much significance as the building now known as the Golden Gate Hotel &amp;amp; Casino. Before it was the Golden Gate, however, it was the Sal Sagev Hotel – a name born from a clever trick and reflecting the unique character of early Fremont Street. Its story is a window into the Las Vegas of yesteryear, a far cry from the glittering Strip we know today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Sands Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Legend</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sands-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sands-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-strip-landmark-the-sands-early-years&#34;&gt;A Strip Landmark: The Sands&amp;rsquo; Early Years&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Sands Hotel and Casino. Just the name conjures up images of smoky casinos, dazzling lights, and the legendary Rat Pack. Opened on December 5, 1952, as the seventh resort on the Las Vegas Strip, the Sands quickly became more than just a hotel and casino; it was &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to be. Initially built by Jake Freedman and designed by architect Wayne McAllister, the Sands boasted a striking 56-foot sign that cut through the desert night, a beacon of entertainment and luxury. Starting with just 200 rooms, it aimed to attract a sophisticated clientele, a stark contrast to the more rough-and-tumble casinos that preceded it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Sands: A Vintage Vegas Legend Demolished</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-sands-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-sands-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-sands-where-glamour-and-the-rat-pack-ruled&#34;&gt;The Sands: Where Glamour and the Rat Pack Ruled&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Sands Hotel and Casino, a name synonymous with vintage Las Vegas, stood as a beacon on the Strip for over four decades. Opening its doors on December 5, 1952, as the seventh resort to grace the burgeoning Las Vegas Strip, it wasn’t just a hotel and casino; it was a cultural phenomenon. Initially the brainchild of Jake Freedman, the Sands quickly established itself as a playground for the elite and a mecca for entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Sans Souci Hotel and Casino: A Vintage Vegas Gem Lost to Time</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sans-souci-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sans-souci-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-auto-court-to-strip-icon-the-early-years&#34;&gt;From Auto Court to Strip Icon: The Early Years&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling lights, the Las Vegas Strip was a much different place. Located at 3320 Las Vegas Boulevard South, across from the legendary Sands Hotel, the Sans Souci Hotel and Casino was a vital part of that evolving landscape. Its story began in the 1930s as the Mountain View Auto Court, catering to weary travelers on U.S. Highway 91 – the very road that would become the Strip. This modest auto court provided a crucial stopping point for those journeying across the desert. The pivotal change came in 1939 with a new name: the Sans Souci, French for “without a care.” This instantly evoked a sense of relaxed luxury and signaled an ambition for something more than a simple motor lodge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Santa Fe Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Oasis for Locals</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/santa-fe-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/santa-fe-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-different-kind-of-vegas-dream-the-santa-fes-arrival&#34;&gt;A Different Kind of Vegas Dream: The Santa Fe&amp;rsquo;s Arrival&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip gets all the glory, but a different kind of Vegas story unfolded just a few miles away. In February 1991, the Santa Fe Hotel and Casino opened its doors at 4949 North Rancho Drive, a bold experiment in catering not to tourists, but to the growing population of Las Vegas residents. Developed by Paul Lowden’s Santa Fe Gaming Corporation, it was a deliberate departure from the glitz and glamour of the Strip, aiming instead to be a full-scale resort for families and locals in the underserved northwest valley.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Showboat Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Vegas Riverboat Dream</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/showboat-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/showboat-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-mississippi-dream-in-the-desert&#34;&gt;A Mississippi Dream in the Desert&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vintage Las Vegas wasn&amp;rsquo;t just about the glitz and glamour of the Strip. It was also about creating unique experiences, catering to locals, and building community. The Showboat Hotel and Casino, opening its doors on September 3, 1954, perfectly embodied that spirit. Located at 2800 Fremont Street (well before the Strip became what it is today), the Showboat was a bold concept: a riverboat-themed casino in the middle of the Nevada desert.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Silver Nugget Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Treasure</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silver-nugget-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silver-nugget-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-north-las-vegas-institution-the-silver-nuggets-story&#34;&gt;A North Las Vegas Institution: The Silver Nugget&amp;rsquo;s Story&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The bright neon glow of the Silver Nugget Casino is now sadly extinguished, but its legacy remains a vibrant thread in the tapestry of Las Vegas history. Located at 2140 Las Vegas Boulevard North, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t your glitzy Strip behemoth. It was a classic locals’ casino, a community hub, and a testament to a different era of Las Vegas entertainment. Opened in 1964, the Silver Nugget was the brainchild of entrepreneur Major Riddle, a name already familiar to Vegas insiders for his contributions to the Dunes Hotel and his willingness to push boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Silver Slipper: A Vintage Las Vegas Strip Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silver-slipper-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silver-slipper-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-glimmer-of-silver-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Glimmer of Silver on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those of us who remember the &amp;lsquo;glory days&amp;rsquo; of the Las Vegas Strip, the Silver Slipper Hotel and Casino holds a special place in our memories. Opened on September 1, 1950, in Winchester, Nevada (which would soon become part of Las Vegas), the Silver Slipper was more than just another casino; it was a distinctive landmark positioned strategically near the bustling Frontier Hotel and Casino. Interestingly, both properties shared the same ownership initially, creating a symbiotic relationship that contributed to their success.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Silverbird Hotel and Casino: A Lost Gem of Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silverbird-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silverbird-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-thunderbird-to-silverbird-a-new-vision-for-value&#34;&gt;From Thunderbird to Silverbird: A New Vision for Value&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen its share of transformations, but few stories are as poignant as that of the Silverbird Hotel and Casino. Originally the Thunderbird Hotel, a long-standing fixture on the Strip, it embarked on a brief but ambitious reinvention in the mid-1970s. In December 1976, Major Riddle, a local businessman, acquired the property with a bold plan: to rename it the Silverbird and revitalize its image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Somerset House: A Vintage Las Vegas Oasis Just Off the Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/somerset-house-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/somerset-house-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-quiet-contributor-to-vegass-growth&#34;&gt;A Quiet Contributor to Vegas&amp;rsquo;s Growth&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas history isn’t just about the dazzling Strip casinos. It’s about the countless motels, hotels, and businesses that quietly fueled the city&amp;rsquo;s expansion, catering to a diverse clientele. Among these, the Somerset House Motel, located at 294 Convention Center Drive, stands as a poignant reminder of a bygone era. Opened in 1963, this three-story, 104-room motor inn occupied a strategic position just east of the Strip, nestled between the iconic Stardust and the burgeoning Las Vegas Convention Center.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Stardust: A Vintage Vegas Icon&#39;s Rise and Fall</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/stardust-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/stardust-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-star-is-born-the-stardusts-grand-entrance&#34;&gt;A Star is Born: The Stardust&amp;rsquo;s Grand Entrance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be what it is today without the Stardust Hotel and Casino. Opened on July 2, 1958, it was a behemoth. Imagine: 1,065 rooms, a sprawling 16,500 square foot casino, and a whopping 60 acres of land! It was, quite simply, the largest hotel in the world at the time. The story began with Tony Cornero, who initially spearheaded the project. Following his untimely death in 1955, his brother took over until Rella Factor finalized the deal and brought the Stardust to life. Its sheer scale set it apart, and its location – just south of the burgeoning center of the Strip – cemented its place in Las Vegas history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Sundance: A Brief, Brilliant Spark in Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sundance-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/sundance-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-kind-of-downtown-the-sundance-arrives&#34;&gt;A New Kind of Downtown: The Sundance Arrives&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For decades, Fremont Street was synonymous with nickel slots, gritty charm, and a raw, unvarnished Vegas experience. But in 1980, a newcomer arrived on the scene with a different vision: The Sundance Hotel &amp;amp; Casino. Built on land owned by the legendary Moe Dalitz, a figure inextricably linked to Las Vegas’s organized crime past, the Sundance aimed to elevate Downtown. It wasn’t about tearing down the old – it was about adding a touch of modern luxury to the mix.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Tam O’Shanter Motel: A Vintage Las Vegas Strip Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tam-oshanter-motel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tam-oshanter-motel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-friendly-face-on-the-strip-introducing-the-tam-oshanter-motel&#34;&gt;A Friendly Face on the Strip: Introducing the Tam O’Shanter Motel&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and sprawling complexes dominated the Las Vegas Strip, there were the classic motor courts – charming, family-run establishments that offered a welcoming respite for travelers. Among the most memorable of these was the Tam O’Shanter Motel, a beloved landmark located at 3317 South Las Vegas Boulevard, nestled between the iconic Sands and Desert Inn. Opened in 1959 by Bernie Zeldin, this 100-room inn was more than just a place to sleep; it was a symbol of a different era of Vegas hospitality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Thunderbird Hotel and Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Icon</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/thunderbird-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/thunderbird-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-southwest-welcome-on-the-early-strip&#34;&gt;A Southwest Welcome on the Early Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wasn’t always the sprawling behemoth it is today. Back in 1948, it was a fledgling stretch of highway (Highway 91, now the Strip) with just a handful of resorts vying for the attention of visitors. Among them stood the Thunderbird Hotel and Casino, a vibrant addition to the evolving landscape and a symbol of early Vegas ambition.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Opened on September 2, 1948, the Thunderbird wasn&amp;rsquo;t initially destined to be the Thunderbird. Originally planned as the “Nevada Ambassador,” the name change reflected a shift towards a distinctly Southwestern theme. Developers Marion Hicks (who previously built the El Cortez) and Nevada’s Lieutenant Governor Clifford A. Jones, along with Joe Wells (father of the beloved Dawn Wells), envisioned a resort that would capture the spirit of the region. While the initial budget was set at $1 million, the soaring costs of construction ultimately exceeded $2 million – a significant sum in those days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Tillerman: A Vintage Las Vegas Steakhouse Oasis</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-tillerman-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-tillerman-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-quiet-dignity-on-east-flamingo-introducing-the-tillerman&#34;&gt;A Quiet Dignity on East Flamingo: Introducing The Tillerman&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we think of vintage Las Vegas, the glittering casinos and elaborate showgirl productions often spring to mind. But beyond the Strip’s relentless sparkle, there existed a different kind of magic – the warm, inviting ambiance of a classic steakhouse. And for over three decades, The Tillerman, located at 2245 E. Flamingo Road, offered just that. Opened in 1980, it stood as a notable alternative to the often-overwhelming glitz of the Strip’s dining rooms, attracting both locals and savvy visitors seeking a more refined, relaxed experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Tip Top Drive-In: A Vintage Slice of Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tip-top-drive-in-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tip-top-drive-in-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-neon-oasis-on-the-strip-introducing-the-tip-top-drive-in&#34;&gt;A Neon Oasis on the Strip: Introducing the Tip Top Drive-In&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and sprawling casinos dominated the Las Vegas Strip, there existed a different kind of magic – the charm of the roadside diner. Among these cherished establishments was the Tip Top Drive-In, a neon landmark that held a special place in the hearts of locals and travelers alike. Located at 1100 South Las Vegas Boulevard, at the intersection of Charleston Boulevard, the Tip Top represented a quintessential Las Vegas experience from its opening in January 1959.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering The Treasury Hotel &amp; Casino: A Quirky Chapter in Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-treasury-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-treasury-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-rapid-fire-of-names--transformations-on-tropicana&#34;&gt;A Rapid Fire of Names &amp;amp; Transformations on Tropicana&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip’s history isn’t just about the iconic casinos we know today. It’s a landscape of constant evolution, rebranding, and often, forgotten chapters. One such chapter belongs to the property currently known as the OYO Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, formerly The Treasury Hotel &amp;amp; Casino. Its story is a whirlwind of name changes, architectural experiments, and a brief but memorable foray into a decidedly unique theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Top O’ The Dunes Restaurant: A Vintage Las Vegas Icon</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/top-o-the-dunes-restaurant-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/top-o-the-dunes-restaurant-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-birds-eye-view-of-old-vegas&#34;&gt;A Bird&amp;rsquo;s-Eye View of Old Vegas&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been about spectacle, but few experiences rivaled the magic of dining at Top O’ The Dunes Restaurant. Perched atop the Dunes Hotel &amp;amp; Casino’s 21-story “Diamond of the Dunes” tower, opening initially as “Top O’ The Strip” in June 1965, this wasn’t just a restaurant; it was an event. Imagine: a sophisticated, dimly lit room, plush seating, and, most importantly, panoramic views stretching across the Strip, downtown, and the vast Nevada desert – a truly unparalleled vista.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Vacation Village: A Quirky Chapter in Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/vacation-village-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/vacation-village-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-long-time-coming-the-dream-of-vacation-village&#34;&gt;A Long Time Coming: The Dream of Vacation Village&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just south of the glittering main Las Vegas Strip, nestled on a plot of land initially acquired by the Heers family as early as 1964, sat a resort that epitomized a different era of Vegas: the Vacation Village Hotel and Casino. While the Strip was becoming increasingly synonymous with opulent mega-resorts, Vacation Village carved out a niche as a more modest, value-driven escape. The story of its realization, however, was anything but straightforward. Initial plans emerged in the 1970s, only to stall. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until 1988 that the project was revived, finally debuting in November 1990.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rolling Back the Years: The History of the Par-A-Dice Motel Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/par-a-dice-motel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/par-a-dice-motel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-lucky-name-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Lucky Name on Fremont Street&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and high-roller suites, Las Vegas thrived on a charming, accessible roadside vibe. A key part of that early identity was the Par‑A‑Dice Motel, a beloved fixture on Fremont Street from 1953 until its closure in the early 2010s. Located at 2217 Fremont Street, the motel’s name itself was a clever play on words, capitalizing on the city’s burgeoning gambling culture. The dice imagery – prominently featured on its signage – was a simple, yet effective way to attract the countless travelers passing through.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver Palace Las Vegas: A Forgotten Pioneer of Fremont Street&#39;s Modern Era</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silver-palace-las-vegas-versino-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silver-palace-las-vegas-versino-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-modern-marvel-on-fremont-street-the-silver-palaces-debut&#34;&gt;A Modern Marvel on Fremont Street: The Silver Palace&amp;rsquo;s Debut&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mid-1950s in Las Vegas were a time of rapid change. While the classic, single-story casinos of Fremont Street held their own, a new wave of ambition sought to modernize the city’s entertainment scene. Enter the Silver Palace Casino, which dramatically debuted in June 1956 at 32 East Fremont Street – a location now occupied by Circa Resort and Casino. Owned by the Spinning Wheel Corporation, the Silver Palace wasn’t just another casino; it was a statement.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steamboat Dreams &amp; Carnival Nights: A Look Back at the Holiday Casino Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holiday-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/holiday-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-steamboat-on-the-strip-the-birth-of-the-holiday-casino&#34;&gt;A Steamboat on the Strip: The Birth of the Holiday Casino&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has seen countless transformations, but few stories are as charmingly unique as that of the Holiday Casino. Opened on July 2, 1973, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t just another casino; it was a bold attempt to capture the romance of the Mississippi River in the heart of the desert. Initially planned as the &amp;lsquo;River Queen,&amp;rsquo; the casino, developed by Holiday Queen Land Corporation in partnership with Holiday Inn, offered a refreshing alternative to the increasingly opulent and exclusive casinos that were becoming the norm. Shelby and Claudine Williams, owners of the Silver Slipper, envisioned a place for everyday gamblers, and their vision paid off handsomely. The adjacent Holiday Inn Center Strip hotel, opening in 1972, laid the groundwork, creating a convenient and accessible destination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steiner Cleaners and Laundry: The Secret Weapon of Las Vegas’s Stars | Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/steiner-cleaners-and-laundry-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/steiner-cleaners-and-laundry-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-than-just-a-laundry-the-story-of-steiner-cleaners-and-laundry-las-vegas&#34;&gt;More Than Just a Laundry: The Story of Steiner Cleaners and Laundry Las Vegas&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you think of Las Vegas, images of dazzling lights, elaborate shows, and legendary performers likely come to mind. But behind the glitz and glamour lies a network of businesses that quietly supported the entertainment machine. And few were as crucial – or as fascinating – as Steiner Cleaners and Laundry. Founded in the early 1960s by Herman Steiner, this seemingly ordinary establishment became an extraordinary fixture in the Las Vegas Strip&amp;rsquo;s history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bird Cage Casino: A Fleeting Neon Flash on Vintage Las Vegas&#39; Fremont Street</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bird-cage-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bird-cage-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-cage-full-of-big-dreams-introducing-the-bird-cage-casino&#34;&gt;A Cage Full of Big Dreams: Introducing the Bird Cage Casino&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fremont Street in the 1950s was a whirlwind of ambition and neon, a place where dreams were gambled on and fortunes (sometimes) won. Amidst the legendary casinos of the era – the Mint, California Club, and Nevada Club – stood a brief but visually striking landmark: the Bird Cage Casino. Located at the coveted “Lucky Corner” of First and Fremont (now part of Circa Resort and Casino), the Bird Cage, operational from January 1, 1958, to late 1959, left a lasting impression despite its short run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Enduring Charm of El Cortez Hotel &amp; Casino: A Vintage Las Vegas Landmark</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-cortez-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-cortez-hotel-and-casino-las-legas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-downtown-dynasty-the-el-cortez-story&#34;&gt;A Downtown Dynasty: The El Cortez Story&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas history is filled with iconic names and legendary spots, and nestled just a block from the dazzling Fremont Street Experience stands one of the most enduring: the El Cortez Hotel and Casino. Opened on November 7, 1941, by Guy McAfee, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t just another casino; it was a crucial piece of the developing Las Vegas landscape. Back then, Las Vegas wasn’t the sprawling metropolis we know today. It was a dusty desert town slowly transforming into an entertainment destination, and the El Cortez, initially offering 48 rooms and a small casino, was right in the thick of it. Its location, close to Fremont Street (then the main drag!), made it a natural hub for early visitors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The International Hotel: A Bold Gamble That Shaped Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/international-hotel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/international-hotel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-vision-beyond-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Vision Beyond the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the Westgate Las Vegas, before even the Las Vegas Hilton, stood the International Hotel, a monument to Kirk Kerkorian&amp;rsquo;s ambitious vision for the burgeoning Las Vegas landscape. The story begins not with grand designs, but with a racetrack – the Las Vegas Park. In 1965, real estate developer Marvin Kratter initially acquired the land, envisioning a sprawling development complete with a hotel, golf course, and luxury homes. However, his plans didn&amp;rsquo;t fully materialize, leaving a prime piece of real estate ripe for a new opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mirage: How a Volcano and Vision Redefined Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mirage-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/mirage-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-tropical-oasis-arrives-on-the-desert-strip&#34;&gt;A Tropical Oasis Arrives on the Desert Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the Venetian’s canals, before the Bellagio’s fountains, there was The Mirage. Opening its doors on November 22, 1989, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t just another casino; it was a statement. For over 15 years, the Las Vegas Strip had remained relatively unchanged. Then, Steve Wynn, armed with a bold vision and a hefty $630 million budget (financed largely through, controversially, junk bonds), unleashed The Mirage upon the world. That price tag made it the most expensive resort &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt; built at the time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Moulin Rouge: A Brief, Brilliant Spark in Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/moulin-rouge-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/moulin-rouge-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-casino-that-broke-the-color-barrier&#34;&gt;A Casino That Broke the Color Barrier&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas in the 1950s was a city defined by stark racial divides. While the Strip glittered with promise, it largely remained off-limits to Black patrons, relegating them to the role of employees or occasional entertainers. Downtown, too, was largely segregated. Then came the Moulin Rouge, a bold experiment that briefly illuminated a path toward integration. Opened on May 24, 1955, at 900 West Bonanza Road, it stood between the glittering Strip and the historically Black West Las Vegas neighborhood – a strategic location designed to serve a wider clientele.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Royal Nevada: A Short, Sparkling Reign on Vintage Las Vegas Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-nevada-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/royal-nevada-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-crown-briefly-adorning-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Crown Briefly Adorning the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 1950s were a whirlwind of growth for Las Vegas, and the Strip was ground zero for this rapid expansion. Amidst the boom, the Royal Nevada Hotel and Casino appeared in 1955, a bold attempt to carve out a space for itself. Originally planned as the “Sunrise Hotel,” the name was changed, and the grand vision of hotelier Frank Fishman became a reality – albeit a short one. Its April 19, 1955, opening marked the debut of the Strip’s eighth resort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Shenandoah Hotel Las Vegas: A Fallen Star on Flamingo Road | Vintage Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/shenandoah-hotel-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/shenandoah-hotel-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-grand-ambition-a-swift-fall-the-story-of-the-shenandoah-hotel&#34;&gt;A Grand Ambition, a Swift Fall: The Story of the Shenandoah Hotel&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The early 1980s were a time of booming growth and dizzying ambition in Las Vegas. New hotels and casinos popped up constantly, each vying to be the biggest and the best. Among these fleeting stars was the Shenandoah Hotel, a project initially conceived as a luxurious casino resort that burned bright for only a few years before fading into the desert dust. Located at 120 E. Flamingo Road, just east of the burgeoning Las Vegas Strip, the Shenandoah’s story is a poignant reminder that even the most dazzling visions can be undone by regulatory hurdles and financial realities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Short, Turbulent Life of the Nevada Palace Hotel and Casino: A Vintage Vegas Story</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/nevada-palace-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/nevada-palace-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-bold-bet-on-the-east-side&#34;&gt;A Bold Bet on the East Side&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the late 1970s, Las Vegas was expanding, and the East Side (now Boulder Highway) was a prime target for growth. Enter the Nevada Palace Hotel and Casino, which opened its doors on July 3, 1979. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t a behemoth resort; it started small with just 100 hotel rooms and a 15,000-square-foot casino. The dream team behind it – casino veterans Gene Lucas, Robert Mariscal, Bill Gallagher, Dan Straub, and Rene Diaz – envisioned a successful, community-focused property. The design was classic 70s Vegas – bold colors, neon, and a generally optimistic vibe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Silver Palace Casino Las Vegas: A Downtown Landmark&#39;s Brief but Brilliant Reign</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silver-palace-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/silver-palace-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-modern-marvel-on-fremont-street-the-silver-palace-arrives&#34;&gt;A Modern Marvel on Fremont Street: The Silver Palace Arrives&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downtown Las Vegas in the 1950s was a vibrant, competitive landscape. While the established casinos along Fremont Street were drawing crowds, a new wave of innovation was brewing. Enter the Silver Palace Casino, opening its doors on June 8, 1956, at 32 East Fremont Street. Owned by the Spinning Wheel Corporation, the Silver Palace wasn’t just another casino; it was a statement. Construction began in 1955, and the finished product was undeniably modern – a two-story structure unlike anything seen previously on Fremont.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tallyho Hotel: A Brief, Bold, and Forgotten Dream on the Las Vegas Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tallyho-hotel-and-country-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tallyho-hotel-and-country-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-luxurious-gamble-that-didnt-pay-off-the-tallyho-hotel-and-country-club&#34;&gt;A Luxurious Gamble That Didn&amp;rsquo;t Pay Off: The Tallyho Hotel and Country Club&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip is known for extravagance, innovation, and, above all, gambling. But in December 1962, a bold experiment challenged that very formula. Enter the Tallyho Hotel and Country Club, a luxury retreat unlike anything seen before (or since) on the Strip.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;edwin-lowes-vision-a-non-gaming-oasis&#34;&gt;Edwin Lowe&amp;rsquo;s Vision: A Non-Gaming Oasis&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mastermind behind this unusual venture was Edwin S. Lowe, a name familiar to many for his role in popularizing Bingo and launching the iconic game Yahtzee. Lowe envisioned a sophisticated, non-gaming escape, a European-style country club experience transplanted to the Nevada desert. Situated directly across from the legendary Dunes Hotel, the Tallyho’s English Tudor architecture stood in stark contrast to the burgeoning modern aesthetic that was beginning to define the Strip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tropicana Las Vegas: A Rose-Colored Farewell to a Vintage Vegas Icon</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tropicana-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/tropicana-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-lush-oasis-arrives-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Lush Oasis Arrives on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the Tropicana Hotel and Casino burst onto the Las Vegas Strip on April 4, 1957, it was a splash of exotic color and sophistication. Costing a then-astronomical $25 million, it instantly became the most expensive resort in Las Vegas. Spanning 35 acres and boasting 1,467 rooms and a 44,570 square foot casino, the Tropicana was designed to evoke a South Seas paradise, a stark contrast to the desert landscape. The sprawling gardens, vibrant floral displays (the iconic flamingo motif!), and the distinctive, romantic architecture made it instantly recognizable and a hit with visitors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Villa Deste Restaurant and Lounge Las Vegas: A Mob-Built Oasis of Old-World Glamour | Vintage Las Vegas History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/villa-deste-restaurant-and-lounge-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/villa-deste-restaurant-and-lounge-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-slice-of-italy-courtesy-of-the-mob-introducing-villa-deste&#34;&gt;A Slice of Italy, Courtesy of the Mob: Introducing Villa Deste&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been about spectacle, but sometimes, what truly defined an era was the understated elegance that existed just beyond the neon lights. Enter Villa Deste Restaurant and Lounge, a beloved institution that operated from 1963 until its closure, leaving behind a legacy of impeccable service, authentic Italian cuisine, and a fascinating, often-overlooked connection to Las Vegas’s darker past. Located just off the Strip, Villa Deste wasn’t just a restaurant; it was an experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Las Vegas: A Look Back at Girls of Glitter Gulch – Fremont Street&#39;s Iconic Gentlemen&#39;s Club</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/girls-of-glitter-gultch-gentlemens-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/girls-of-glitter-gultch-gentlemens-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-golden-goose-to-girls-of-glitter-gulch-a-fremont-street-evolution&#34;&gt;From Golden Goose to Girls of Glitter Gulch: A Fremont Street Evolution&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Fremont Street Experience is synonymous with old-school Vegas, but beneath the dazzling Viva Vision light show lies a rich and often-forgotten history. Today, Circa Resort &amp;amp; Casino stands proudly on Fremont Street, but before it rose from the desert dust, the land was home to a landmark in Vegas nightlife: Girls of Glitter Gulch, a gentlemen’s club with a story all its own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Las Vegas: A Look Back at Girls of Glitter Gulch Gentlemen&#39;s Club</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/girls-of-glitter-gultch-gentlemans-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/girls-of-glitter-gultch-gentlemans-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-golden-goose-to-girls-of-glitter-gulch-a-fremont-street-story&#34;&gt;From Golden Goose to Girls of Glitter Gulch: A Fremont Street Story&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Fremont Street Experience is a vibrant spectacle today, but it wasn’t always so polished. For decades, the area, once known as “Glitter Gulch,” thrived on a different kind of energy – a raucous, adult-oriented atmosphere fueled by iconic (and sometimes scandalous) establishments. Among these was Girls of Glitter Gulch, a gentlemen’s club that holds a unique place in Las Vegas history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Vegas Racing: Remembering the Derby Turf Club &amp; Its Race Betting Legacy</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/derby-turf-club-race-betting-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/derby-turf-club-race-betting-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-fremont-street-favorite-the-derby-turf-clubs-race-betting-past&#34;&gt;A Fremont Street Favorite: The Derby Turf Club&amp;rsquo;s Race Betting Past&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 1950s and 60s in Las Vegas were a time of rapid growth and exciting innovation. While the Strip was evolving into the entertainment mecca we know today, Downtown, clustered around Fremont Street, thrived with a different kind of energy - a raw, gambling-focused vibe. Among the establishments contributing to that distinct character was the Derby Turf Club, a dedicated race and sports book that left its mark on Las Vegas history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Vegas: A Gaming Guide to the Lost Bank Club Casino on Fremont Street</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bank-club-casino-gaming-guide-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/bank-club-casino-gaming-guide-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-glimpse-into-fremont-streets-first-flush-the-bank-club-casino&#34;&gt;A Glimpse into Fremont Street’s First Flush: The Bank Club Casino&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas. The name conjures images of glittering high-rises, sprawling resorts, and non-stop entertainment. But the Vegas of the 1930s and 40s looked vastly different. Before the Strip became &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; Strip, Fremont Street was the beating heart of legal casino gaming in Nevada. And nestled within that bustling downtown core, at 17 Fremont Street, stood the Bank Club Casino – a small, but significant, player in the city’s formative years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Vegas: A Look Back at the Enduring Legacy of the El Cortez Hotel &amp; Casino</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-cortez-hotel-and-casino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/el-cortez-hotel-and-casino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-downtown-staple-the-el-cortezs-early-years&#34;&gt;A Downtown Staple: The El Cortez’s Early Years&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you think of vintage Las Vegas, images of the dazzling Fremont Street Experience likely come to mind. But a block away from that vibrant thoroughfare stands a quieter, yet equally significant, testament to the city’s early days: the El Cortez Hotel and Casino. Opened on November 7, 1941, just as the nation was entering World War II, the El Cortez (often affectionately called “El Co”) wasn’t part of the nascent “Strip” of casinos – downtown &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; Las Vegas back then. It was built by William Keeler and Orle Williams, who initially named it the El Rancho Vegas, but it was later renamed. Its presence signaled a burgeoning entertainment district centered around Fremont Street.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Vegas: Remembering the Nevada Club Casino – A Fremont Street Gem</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/nevada-club-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/nevada-club-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-downtown-classic-the-nevada-clubs-rise-on-fremont-street&#34;&gt;A Downtown Classic: The Nevada Club&amp;rsquo;s Rise on Fremont Street&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and sprawling Strip, downtown Las Vegas, known as Glitter Gulch, pulsed with a unique energy. Amongst its vital organs was the Nevada Club Casino, a now-vanished landmark located at 113 East Fremont Street. Squeezed between the Lucky Strike and the burgeoning Golden Nugget, the Nevada Club was a quintessential mid-century casino, a testament to a more approachable and boisterous era of Las Vegas gambling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Vegas: Remembering the New Frontier Hotel &amp; Casino – and That Iconic Ladies V-Neck!</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-frontier-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas-ladies-v-neck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/the-frontier-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas-ladies-v-neck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-frontier-spirit-on-the-strip&#34;&gt;A Frontier Spirit on the Strip&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Frontier Hotel and Casino, later rebranded as the New Frontier, holds a unique place in Las Vegas Strip history. Opened in 1942 as the Apache Hotel, it quickly became “The Frontier” to capitalize on the post-war Western craze. It stood as a symbol of the burgeoning Las Vegas – a place offering affordable entertainment and a gritty, energetic atmosphere that drew a different crowd than the more upscale resorts beginning to emerge. Unlike the glitz and glamour of the Sands or the Flamingo, the Frontier catered largely to a middle-class clientele, families, and those seeking a more casual gaming experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Vegas: Remembering the Whimsical Money Tree Casino on the Strip</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/money-tree-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/money-tree-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-little-luck-and-a-lot-of-charm-the-money-tree-casino&#34;&gt;A Little Luck and a Lot of Charm: The Money Tree Casino&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip has always been a landscape of contrasts – towering megaresorts casting shadows on humble, neighborhood joints. Among those smaller casinos that once thrived alongside the giants was the Money Tree Casino, a unique and fondly remembered piece of vintage Las Vegas history. Opening its doors in the early 1970s, the Money Tree offered a distinctly different experience than the glitz and glamour associated with the Strip’s rising behemoths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Vegas: The Legendary Horseshoe Hotel and Casino – A Downtown Icon</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/horseshoe-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/horseshoe-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-downtown-revolution-the-birth-of-the-horseshoe&#34;&gt;A Downtown Revolution: The Birth of the Horseshoe&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the sprawling mega-resorts of the Las Vegas Strip dominated the skyline, downtown Fremont Street was the heart of Las Vegas gaming. And in 1951, Benny Binion arrived and fundamentally altered its pulse. He opened the Horseshoe Hotel and Casino at 128 Fremont Street, not with flash and fanfare, but with a commitment to fair odds and a gambler&amp;rsquo;s paradise. This wasn’t about stuffy formality; it was about welcoming players of all levels and treating everyone with respect – a radical shift from the existing casino culture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Vegas: The Nevada Club - A Slot Machine War &amp; Strip History</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/nevada-club-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/nevada-club-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-turf-club-to-a-casino-powerhouse-the-early-days-of-the-nevada-club&#34;&gt;From Turf Club to a Casino Powerhouse: The Early Days of the Nevada Club&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Nevada Club, a name that resonates with vintage Las Vegas charm, didn&amp;rsquo;t begin as we remember it. Its story starts in 1952, when it acquired the Santa Anita Turf Club, a modest operation already nestled on the burgeoning Las Vegas Strip. This marked the beginning of a rapid ascent that would see the club become a central player in the city’s booming casino scene. The early 50s were a period of significant growth for Las Vegas, and the Nevada Club was positioned right in the thick of it, catering to a clientele seeking a more sophisticated gambling experience than some of the older downtown casinos offered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vintage Vegas: The Nevada Club Hotel &amp; Casino – A Strip Pioneer and Slot Machine Innovator</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/nevada-club-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/nevada-club-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-turf-club-to-a-strip-staple-the-early-years&#34;&gt;From Turf Club to a Strip Staple: The Early Years&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before the mega-resorts and dazzling fountains, the Las Vegas Strip was a collection of smaller, scrappier casinos vying for attention. Among them stood the Nevada Club Hotel &amp;amp; Casino, a vital piece of that early landscape. Its story began in 1952, not as the Nevada Club, but as the Santa Anita Turf Club. A relatively simple operation initially, it was quickly scooped up and rebranded, laying the groundwork for what would become a significant (and noisy!) landmark.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
