<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pair a Dice Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</title>
    <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/pair-a-dice-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pair a Dice Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/pair-a-dice-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lost &amp; Found: The Forgotten History of Pair A Dice Hotel &amp; Casino in Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pair-a-dice-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/pair-a-dice-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-dicey-beginning-the-pair-a-dice-arrives-1956&#34;&gt;A Dicey Beginning: The Pair-A-Dice Arrives (1956)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wasn&amp;rsquo;t always the glittering behemoth it is today. In the 1950s, development was spreading north along Las Vegas Boulevard, and a surprising number of smaller, independent casinos popped up. Among these was the Pair-A-Dice Hotel and Casino, which opened its doors in 1956 at 2067 North Las Vegas Boulevard. While not boasting the grandeur of the Flamingo or the Sands, the Pair-A-Dice represented a vital part of the burgeoning North Strip landscape. Information about its early ownership and specific features remains scarce – a testament to how quickly it faded from the collective Vegas memory – but it likely offered the typical fare of the era: slots, a small poker room, and a modest lounge. Its location, further north than the established &amp;ldquo;center&amp;rdquo; of the Strip, meant it catered to a slightly different clientele, perhaps those looking for a more relaxed, less pretentious gambling experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
