<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alpine Village Inn Restaurant and Inn Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</title>
    <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/alpine-village-inn-restaurant-and-inn-las-vegas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alpine Village Inn Restaurant and Inn Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/alpine-village-inn-restaurant-and-inn-las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Alpine Village Inn: A Taste of Bavaria in Vintage Las Vegas</title>
      <link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/alpine-village-inn-restaurant-and-inn-las-vegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/alpine-village-inn-restaurant-and-inn-las-vegas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-desert-oasis-of-bavarian-cheer&#34;&gt;A Desert Oasis of Bavarian Cheer&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip’s history is filled with flamboyant themes and larger-than-life experiences, but few establishments cultivated the unique charm of the Alpine Village Inn Restaurant and Inn. From its debut in 1950, this Bavarian-Swiss themed establishment offered a welcome respite from the growing desert city, a taste of Old World hospitality, and a whole lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Founded by Ray Dambach and Pauline Remmert at 905 North Las Vegas Boulevard, the Inn initially catered to a population hungry for something beyond the standard fare. The menu was straightforward – sauerkraut, schnitzel, and hearty potato pancakes – but the ambiance was the real draw. Over the years, the Alpine Village Inn moved several times, each location evolving the experience. The 1953 relocation to Maryland Parkway, followed by a spot across from the Stardust in the Desert Spa Shopping Center, each built upon the Inn’s reputation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
