<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lotus Inn and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/lotus-inn-and-casino-las-vegas/</link><description>Recent content in Lotus Inn and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/lotus-inn-and-casino-las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lost on the Strip: Remembering the Lotus Inn and Casino - Vintage Las Vegas History</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lotus-inn-and-casino-las-vegas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/lotus-inn-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Las Vegas Strip wasn’t always glittering mega-resorts and themed hotels. In fact, a vibrant ecosystem of smaller, independent motels and casinos thrived, catering to a broader spectrum of visitors. One such establishment, now largely forgotten, was the Lotus Inn and Casino. Located at 1213 South Las Vegas Boulevard, it represents a fascinating, transitional period in the city’s evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-blossom-on-the-boulevard-1964-1980s"&gt;A Blossom on the Boulevard (1964-1980s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerging in the mid-1960s, the Lotus Inn was a product of the boom era for roadside motels and casinos. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t one of the headline-grabbing properties, but it offered a distinct appeal. The name itself, &amp;ldquo;Lotus,&amp;rdquo; and the accompanying stylized Asian characters on the marquee, provided a visual identity – a conscious effort to stand out amongst the burgeoning competition. This nod to Asian culture wasn&amp;rsquo;t uncommon during that era, reflecting broader trends in design and branding.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>