<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stardust Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/stardust-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link><description>Recent content in Stardust Hotel and Casino Las Vegas on Vintage Vegas</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vintage-vegas.com/tags/stardust-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lost in the Stardust: A Look Back at a Vegas Icon | Vintage Las Vegas History</title><link>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/stardust-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vintage-vegas.com/posts/stardust-hotel-and-casino-las-vegas/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-galaxy-of-dreams-the-birth-of-the-stardust"&gt;A Galaxy of Dreams: The Birth of the Stardust&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stardust Hotel and Casino. Just the name conjures images of smoky casinos, dazzling lights, and a certain old-school Vegas charm. Built on a sprawling 60-acre plot on the Las Vegas Strip, the Stardust wasn’t just a hotel and casino – it was a statement. Its story, beginning in 1954, is as glittering and complicated as the neon lights that illuminated its facade. The project’s initial visionary was Tony Cornero, an Italian immigrant with big ambitions. Sadly, Cornero&amp;rsquo;s sudden death in 1955 left the project in the hands of his brother. While construction continued, the hotel&amp;rsquo;s true destiny was solidified in 1958 when Rella Factor stepped in, completing the ambitious vision. The grand opening on July 2, 1958, marked a monumental moment: the Stardust was the largest hotel in the world, boasting a staggering 1,065 rooms and a vast 16,500 square foot casino floor.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>